>> Good morning, and welcome to
早上好，欢迎来到
Day 2 of NDNComm 2021.
2021年NDNComm第二天。
We start today with Session 5 on
我们今天从第五场会议开始。
applications which would be
应用程序将会是
chaired by Jeff Burke.
主持人是Jeff Burke。
Jeff is a
~!@#$%^&*()
Professor-in-Residence and the Associate
常驻教授和副教授
Dean for Technology and
技术学院院长
Innovation at UCLA School of Theatre,
加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧学院的创新，
Film and Television,
电影和电视，
where he co-directs the REMAP Center.
他共同指导REMAP中心。
As most of you know,
大多数人都知道，
he has been one of the CO-PI's and
他一直是共同主要研究员之一，并且
Application Lead for
应用负责人
the NSF-funded NDN program.
美国国家科学基金会资助的NDN项目。
Jeff, go ahead, please.
杰夫，请继续。
>> Hi. Happy to be here. We have
嗨。很高兴来到这里。我们有
three talks in this session.
三场演讲。
I'm going to introduce
我将会介绍
them briefly to give
我将会简短地介绍他们，以便给予他们尽可能多的时间来发言。
them as much time as I can to speak.
我会尽可能给他们更多的时间来发言。
We have about 15 minutes for each speaker
我们为每位发言者大约安排了15分钟。
plus five minutes for questions.
再加上五分钟用于提问。
I'll be looking in
我会注意查看
both slack and the blue jeans
Slack和BlueJeans都是
chat to help facilitate questions.
帮助促进问题沟通的聊天工具。
Our first talk by Lan Wang
我们的第一次交谈，由Lan Wang主讲。
at the University of Memphis is mGuard,
在孟菲斯大学的是mGuard，
a secure real-time data distribution
一种安全的实时数据分发系统
system with fine-grained access control.
具有细粒度访问控制的系统。
>> Hello. Can you hear me?
>> 你好。你能听到我说话吗？
>> Oh, sorry. I realized I have
>> 哦，对不起。我意识到我有
a bio that I need to read.
一个简历，我需要阅读。
That is a Professor and Chair of
这是一位教授兼系主任。
the Department of Computer Science
计算机科学系
at the University of Memphis.
在孟菲斯大学。
She's been working on NDN since
她自2010年起一直在研究NDN（命名数据网络）。
2010 focusing on routing,
自2010年起专注于路由，
forwarding strategies,
转发策略，
Sync, and application development.
同步与应用程序开发。
>> Thank you. Let me see if I can share.
>> 谢谢。让我看看我能不能分享屏幕。
Can you see my screen?
你能看到我的屏幕吗？
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Hello, okay.
>> 你好，好的。
[NOISE]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Go full screen.
>> 全屏显示。
>> Yeah, can you see the full screen?
>> 是的，你能看到全屏显示吗？
>> Can you see it, Jeff?
>> 杰夫，你能看到吗？
>> We're still seeing speaker view right now.
>> 我们现在还是在看演讲者视图。
>> Yeah.
>> 是的。
>> Can you see the full screen?
>> 你能看到全屏吗？
No? Let me try again.
不行吗？我再试一次。
>> You need to stop sharing first then you
>> 首先你需要停止共享屏幕，然后你
select as a full-screen
选择全屏显示
that window. Yeah. Now it's okay.
那个窗口。现在没问题了。
>> Now we see it.
>> 现在我们看到它了。
>> All right. Good morning.
>> 好的。早上好。
I'm going to talk about
我将要讲述
our project called mGuard.
我们的项目叫做mGuard。
It's an effort to
这是一种努力
help mobile health researchers
帮助移动健康研究人员
access data securely and in real-time.
安全且实时地访问数据。
This is a collaboration between
这是一次合作，
the University of Memphis and UCLA,
孟菲斯大学和加州大学洛杉矶分校，
and it's supported by NSF.
并且得到了美国国家科学基金会的支持。
Last year, I actually gave an overview
去年，我实际上给出了一个概述
of the project during NDNComm,
项目在NDNComm期间，
that was at the beginning of the project.
那是在项目开始的时候。
Though I didn't give much detail.
虽然我没有提供太多细节。
This time we've been
这次我们已经
working on the project for one year,
这次我们已经在项目上工作了一年，
so I can give you a progress report.
所以我可以向你报告一下项目进展情况。
First, this project is
所以我可以向你报告一下项目进展情况。首先，这个项目是由一个用例激励的，即
motivated by a use case that
是由一个用例激励的，即
is collecting
是收集
and distributing mobile health data.
和分发移动健康数据。
Basically, our university has
基本上，我们大学有
NIH funded center called MD2K.
国立卫生研究院资助的中心名为MD2K。
They are collecting a lot of
他们正在收集大量的
data from lab studies,
实验室研究的数据。
field studies, from thousands of
实地研究，来自数千个
participants with trillions of data points.
参与者拥有数万亿个数据点。
They want to share the data with
他们想要分享这些数据给
many researchers and also,
许多研究人员也是如此，
study coordinators and
研究协调员和
the study participants themselves.
研究参与者本身。
The question is, right now
问题是，现在
the existing tools or system they are
现有的工具或系统它们
using cannot support
无法支持细粒度访问控制
fine-grained access control
细粒度访问控制
and real-time data distribution.
和实时数据分发。
They cannot, for example,
他们不能，例如，
limit the study coordinator
限制研究协调员
to access only their study,
只能访问他们自己的研究，
not somebody else's study.
不能访问别人的研究。
They cannot limit study participants to
他们不能仅限制研究参与者
access only their own data and that
只能访问他们自己的数据以及
other participants' data, so on and so forth.
他们只能访问其他参与者的数据等等。
They want very flexible access control
他们想要非常灵活的访问控制权限。
but existing systems don't support that.
但现有系统不支持这一点。
[NOISE] Also, they wanted to be
able to give researchers
able to give researchers
能够为研究人员提供
real-time access so they can
及时访问，以便他们能够
provide real-time intervention if
提供实时干预，以便如果
there's any problems with a patient,
出现病人有任何问题时，
for example, but that's not supported.
例如，但那是不被支持的。
What our project wants to do is to apply
我们的项目想要做的是应用
NDN named-based data-centric approaches,
NDN基于名称的数据中心方法，
in particular, Sync and NAC or
特别是同步和基于名称的访问控制或
name-based access control to
解决上述问题。
This is a collaboration with MD2K.
这是与MD2K的合作。
They provide the data and use
他们提供数据并使用
case requirements so we
案例需求，所以我们
can design the mechanisms.
可以设计这些机制。
Here's an overview of the system.
这是系统的概述。
The main components you
主要组件您可以看到的是数据适配器，
can see are the data adapter,
您可以看到的是数据适配器，
publisher, a storage unit,
发布者，一个存储单元，
an access manager, and a subscriber.
一个访问管理器和一个订阅者。
Basically, we take existing data in MD2K to
基本上，我们将MD2K中的现有数据
repository and convert it
将其转换并存储在NDN仓库中。
into NDN data and store it in NDN repos.
转换成NDN数据并存储在NDN仓库中。
Then the data names
然后是数据名称
are provided to the publisher.
提供给出版商。
The publisher will create metadata
出版商将创建元数据
and store the metadata in the repo.
并将元数据存储在仓库中。
At the same time, the publisher
同时，出版商会
is going to advertise
将会进行广告宣传
this information about
这些信息关于
new data to the subscribers.
这些信息关于向订阅者提供新数据。
The subscribers can request any data
订阅者可以请求任何数据
they want from the publisher in real-time.
他们可以从发布者那里实时获取他们想要的数据。
They can subscribe to
他们可以订阅
only a subset of the data streams so that
他们只能订阅数据流的一个子集，以便
they can
他们可以
receive only the data
接收只有数据
of interest to them.
对他们来说感兴趣的。
The access manager will create
访问管理器将创建
the keys for users to decrypt the data.
用户解密数据的密钥。
At the same time,
同时，
the access manager will share
访问管理器将共享
some parameters for the data adapter
数据适配器的一些参数
to encrypt the NDN data.
加密NDN数据。
That's the overall system.
这就是整个系统。
In the first year of this project,
在这个项目的第一年，
we developed the system design
我们开发了系统设计。
and also the NDN naming scheme.
我们还开发了NDN命名方案。
We also developed a policy specification
我们还开发了一种策略规范。
and parser for the access control.
我们还为访问控制开发了解析器。
We extended the existing NAC-ABE library
我们扩展了现有的NAC-ABE库
to support key
以支持密钥
policy attribute-based encryption.
基于属性的加密策略。
We designed a pub-sub API using PSync
我们设计了一个使用PSync的发布-订阅API。
and NAC-ABE to publish
和NAC-ABE来发布
and subscribe to data streams.
并订阅数据流。
I'm going to give more details
我将提供更多细节。
of each of these items.
的每一项。
First of all, the MD2K center collect
首先，MD2K中心收集~!@#$%^&*()
raw data and they also
原始数据，同时他们也会
produce derived data based on the raw data.
基于原始数据产生派生数据。
We named each differently
我们为每一个起了不同的名字。
for the raw data stream.
对于原始数据流。
This data naming scheme is based
这个数据命名方案是基于他们现有的命名，
on their existing naming,
但是我们重新排序了一些组成部分。
It's basically a prefix,
它基本上是一个前缀，
then the study name,
然后是研究名称，
the participant name, and
参与者姓名，以及
device that collect the data,
设备用于收集数据，
sensor,
传感器，
and the attachment where
传感器安装在哪里？
the sensor is attached.
传感器已经安装好了。
Then the derived data
那么派生出的数据
is named the prefix, study,
则被命名为前缀，研究，
then participant and algorithm
则参与者和算法
or package that is
或者是那个包装
used to produce the derived data.
用于生成派生数据。
[NOISE] The specific data point
噪音。具体数据点
has the data streams prefix,
数据流的前缀，
then the keyword data, then a timestamp.
然后是关键字数据，接着是时间戳。
That's how the existing data is labeled.
这就是现有数据的标注方式。
They have their timestamp.
它们有各自的时间戳。
For each data point,
对于每个数据点，
there is a corresponding content key.
每个数据点都有一个相应的内容键。
We also name the content key
我们还给内容键命名
using the same stream prefix
使用相同的流前缀
and a keyword, Ckey.
和一个关键词，Ckey。
As I mentioned before,
正如我之前提到的，
the publisher also creates
出版商还会创建
a manifest or metadata for
出版商还会创建一个清单或元数据来
each data stream so that manifest has
记录每个数据流，以便清单具有
the data streams prefix
跟踪前缀的每个数据流，以便清单具有前缀和清单关键字的序列号。
and manifest keyword in a sequence number.
和清单关键字在序列号中。
Periodically, the publisher
定期地，出版商~!@#$%^&*()
will produce a new manifest with
将会生成一个新的清单，带有
a new sequence number
将生成一个新的序列号
and the subscribers will
以及订阅者将会
be notified when this manifest is created.
在此清单创建时，订阅者将会被通知。
That's how we name the data.
我们就是这样命名数据的。
For the access control,
对于访问控制，
our main goal is to define and
我们的主要目标是定义并
enforce fine-grained rights
实施细粒度的权限控制
to access the data.
访问数据。
What do we mean by that?
我们是什么意思？
That first, we need to
首先，我们需要
support different types of users,
支持不同类型的用户，
data producers, study coordinators,
数据生产者、研究协调员、
and data administrators, for example.
和数据管理员等。
We want to give each user
我们想要给每个用户
minimal access rights based
提供基于最小访问权限的
on the terms of use.
在使用条款上。
Minimal means, you don't get
尽可能少的手段，你不会得到
more than what you're supposed to access.
通过尽可能少的手段，你不会得到比你应该获得的权限更多。We want to support novice users who don't
We want to support novice users who don't
我们希望支持那些不一定拥有非常深入知识的新手用户。
necessarily have very in-depth knowledge
不一定拥有非常深入知识
of security to be able to define a policy.
为了能够定义一项政策，需要具备一定的安全知识。
The policy language should be very simple.
政策语言应该非常简单。
In order to support the above goals,
为了支持上述目标，
we leverage the existing NAC-ABE library
我们利用现有的NAC-ABE库
to encrypt data with content key,
使用内容密钥对数据进行加密，
and then encrypt
然后加密
each content keyword set of attributes
每个内容关键词的属性集合
that can help enforce
可以帮助执行
the access control policy,
执行访问控制策略，
and then we generate,
然后我们生成，
distribute the content keys
分发内容密钥
to the corresponding users,
对应的用户，
so each user has
对应的用户，各自拥有
the key associated with their access rights.
他们访问权限相关联的密钥。
What do we mean by access control policy?
我们所说的访问控制策略是什么意思？
I have an example here.
我这里有一个例子。
First, the data owner defines
首先，数据所有者定义
a set of attributes
一组属性
based on the policy to support,
根据要支持的政策，
and then specifies a set of policies
然后指定了一组政策
containing the attributes that
包含了那些属性
each user is associated with.
每个用户都关联着。
For example, for each policy
例如，对于每项政策，
we have an id identifying the policy,
我们有一个用于识别政策的ID，
and then who are
与此政策相关联的是谁？
associated with this policy,
与此政策相关联的是，
so here is a list of
与此政策相关联的是，这里是一份清单
names corresponding to the users of the data.
与这些数据的用户相对应的名字。
These users are allowed to
这些用户被允许
access data with these attributes,
访问具有这些属性的数据，
and they're not allowed to
他们不被允许这样做
access data with these attributes.
数据所有者需要访问具有这些属性的数据。
The data owner needs to
access data with these attributes.
specify is the list
指定的是列表
of people who can access the data,
可以访问数据的人员名单，
and the allowed attributes,
以及被允许的属性，
and the denied attributes.
和被拒绝的属性。
For example, here's
例如，这里有~!@#$%^&*()
an example policy [NOISE].
一个示例政策[噪音]。
A user, Alice at UCLA can
爱丽丝是UCLA的一名用户，可以
access MD2K data produced by
访问MD2K产生的数据
the mperf study participant
mPerf研究参与者
dd40c when the participant
当参与者
was at home or at work,
在家里或者在工作的时候，
but Alice cannot obtain
但是爱丽丝无法获得
the participants GPS locations.
参与者的GPS位置。
How do we support this policy?
我们如何支持这项政策？
First we specify the name of
首先我们指定名称为
the data user, alice/edu/user/alice,
数据用户，alice/edu/user/alice，
then in the allowed attributes we specify
那么在允许的属性中我们指定
the dataset which is /org/md2k/mperf/dd40c,
我们指定的允许属性中，那就是数据集对应的/org/md2k/mperf/dd40c，
that's the data set corresponding
这就是相应的数据集
to the study participant.
向研究参与者。
Then we say, only when this user is at home,
那么我们就说，只有当这个用户在家的时候，
or this participant is at home or at work,
或者这位参与者在家里或者在工作的时候，
these two attributes identify where
这两个属性用来识别哪里
the location of this study participant,
这项研究参与者的位置，
when the data was produced,
当数据被生成时，
and we specify an attribute
我们指定一个属性
in the denied field, that is,
在被拒绝的字段中，也就是说，
the data name of
数据名称
the GPS location of this user.
这个用户的GPS位置。
That's very simple and intuitive
这非常简单直观。
for a novice user to specify.
对于一个新手用户来说，这是很容易指定的。
That's the control policy.
这就是控制策略。
Now how do we support this policy?
我们现在如何支持这项政策？
As I mentioned before,
正如我之前提到的，
we have a parser that converts
我们有一个解析器，它可以转换
each policy to an expression.
我们有一个解析器，它可以转换每个策略为一个表达式。
For example, if the allowed field
例如，如果允许的字段
has three attributes,
具有三个属性，
we will use the operator or,
我们将使用或运算符，
to connect the attributes of the same time.
来连接相同时间的属性。
These are the location attributes,
这些是位置属性，
so we connect them with or.
所以我们用“或”来连接它们。
For the other I should be
对于另一个，我应该是
we connect it with and.
我们用“和”将其连接起来。
This means the data is
这意味着数据是
produced at home or at work,
产生在家里或者工作场所，
and the data is produced
产生的数据
after September 1st, 2021.
2021年9月1日之后。
This expression or set of
这个表达式或一组~!@#$%^&*()
attributes are encoded into
属性被编码进入
the data users decryption key.
属性被编码进入数据用户的解密密钥。
The data user can only
数据用户只能
access data with these attributes.
访问具有这些属性的数据。
How is this decryption key generated?
这个解密密钥是如何生成的？
It's generated by the access manager
它是由访问管理器生成的。
provided by the NAC-ABE library,
它由NAC-ABE库提供，
it provides automated key management.
它提供了自动化的密钥管理功能。
It can distribute this key to the user,
它可以将这个密钥分发给用户，
and also provide
并且还提供
the necessary encryption parameters
所需的加密参数
for the data publisher
为数据发布者
to encrypt the data with.
用来加密数据。
Because the original implementation supports
由于原始实现支持
only ciphertext policy ABE,
仅支持密文策略属性基加密（CP-ABE），
we extended it to support key policy ABE,
我们将其扩展以支持基于密钥策略的属性加密（KP-ABE），
which means the policy is embedded or
这意味着策略被嵌入或者
encoded in the decryption key because
因为这种方法是更加
this approach is more
适合我们的项目。
How do we distribute the data in real time?
我们如何实时分发数据？
We have defined a Pub-Sub API to allow users
我们定义了一个发布-订阅API以允许用户
to subscribe to data streams as
订阅数据流，按照他们的访问策略所允许的。
permitted by their access policies,
允许的，根据他们的访问策略。
and this Pub-Sub API
和这个发布-订阅 API
guarantees the reception of the latest data,
保证接收到最新的数据，
and it will verify the data
并将验证数据
in each subscribed stream,
在每个订阅的流中，
I can use this piecing to
我可以使用这个拼接来
discover and subscribe to the data streams,
发现并订阅数据流，
and use NAC-ABE to encrypt and decrypt data.
并使用NAC-ABE来加密和解密数据。
The one problem we encountered
我们遇到的一个问题
is there is a lot of
我们遇到的一个问题是有很多小数据对象我们需要
small data objects we need
我们需要的小数据对象
to sign and verify,
进行签名和验证，
and this can incur very high overhead
这可能会导致非常高的开销
if the small data is
如果小数据是
produced at a very high frequency.
产生的频率非常高。
The other solution is to use Manifest.
另一种解决方案是使用Manifest。
Basically the publisher produces
基本上出版商会制作
a series of Manifests for
一系列的清单用于
each data stream with
每个数据流与
this name,
这个名字，
stream-prefix/manifest/sequence number.
流前缀/清单/序列号。
This Manifest contains the full name,
这个清单包含了全名，
including the implicit digest
包括隐式摘要
of the new data objects produced in
新生成的数据对象中
this last period since
这最后一个时期自从
the last manifest was produced.
这最后一份清单被制作出来了。
The subscribers basically
订阅者基本上
receives the manifest and
接收清单并且
retrieves the individual data items
检索各个数据项
or objects corresponding to these names.
或与这些名称对应的对象。
Because the names
因为这些名称
contain the implicit digest,
包含隐式摘要，
the subscriber can verify the retrieved
用户可以验证检索到的
the data matches these implicit digest.
数据与这些隐式摘要匹配。
Each data object is not signed,
每个数据对象都没有签名，
so we can reduce
因此我们可以减少
the overhead of signing and verification,
管理和验证的开销，
we also can reduce the overhead of
我们也可以减少 overhead of
syncing because we're not
因为我们没有进行同步，所以我们也可以减少 overhead of syncing individual objects。
syncing individual objects,
同步单个对象，
we're thinking a set of
我们正在考虑一套
objects at once using the Manifest,
我们正在考虑一套使用清单同时处理多个对象，and piecing makes sure
and piecing makes sure
确保拼接工作
that the subscribers receives the Manifests.
以确保订阅者接收到清单。
Now I'm going to give us summary.
现在我将给我们做一个总结。
But what lessons do we learn?
但我们从中学到了什么教训？
First, we spent a lot
首先，我们花了很多时间尝试去理解
of time trying to understand
我们花了很多时间尝试去理解
the requirements MD2K has for access control.
我们花了很多时间尝试去理解MD2K对访问控制的要求。This is a specific use case,
This is a specific use case,
这是一个特定的用例，
but it gives us a good idea of
但它给了我们一个很好的认识
what requirements for security
对安全性的要求
the mobile health data may have.
移动健康数据可能具有的。
We also spend a lot of time
我们也花了很多时间
trying to understand how we can
我们也花了很多时间尝试理解我们如何能够use NAC-ABE to support
use NAC-ABE to support
使用NAC-ABE来支持
these requirements [NOISE].
这些要求[噪音]。
Previous work, I think, for example,
Previous work, I think, for example, ~!@#$%^&*()
NDN flint used NAC
NDN燧石用了NAC
but it's not the
但这不是
attribute-based encryption version,
基于属性的加密版本，
so we have to think about how do we use
所以我们必须考虑如何使用
attribute-based encryption to support
属性基加密以支持
these requirements.
这些要求。
[NOISE]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Also the policy specification
>> 此外，政策规范
went through several iterations.
经历了多次迭代。
In the beginning we used
起初我们使用
policy specification that's very
接近它们现有的实现的政策规范。
close to their existing implementation,
接近它们现有的实现，
basically specifies for each table
基本上为每个表指定
or each database table,
为每个数据库表，
which columns the user can access,
用户可以访问哪些列，
and what's the value of
和值是多少
the fields that the user can access.
用户可以访问的字段。
Later, we realized that that's not the
后来，我们意识到那不是
best or the most suitable type of
最佳或最合适的类型
specification for
规格说明
the attribute-based access control
基于属性的访问控制
or main attribute-based access control.
或主要基于属性的访问控制。
We realized that we should
我们意识到我们应该
use just the names and
使用仅限名称和~!@#$%^&*()
attributes in the policy specification
在策略规范中的属性
and it actually simply,
这种方法实际上很简单，
this approach simplifies
这种方法简化了
this policy specification
这项政策规范
a lot and it's very intuitive too.
这很多而且也非常直观。
Those are two major lessons
这是两个主要的教训。
we learned. Now the
我们学到了。现在这
>> We're coming up on time.
我们快到时间了。
You want to wrap up?
你想结束了吗？
>> Yeah. There are
是的。有
a few major opening issues. Why is that?
几个主要的开放性问题。这是为什么呢？
There is no negative operator support
没有负操作符支持。
in that KBE,
在那个知识库环境中，
so it's difficult to
在那个知识库环境中，实施拒绝属性是很困难的。
implement the deny attributes.
实施拒绝属性。
Basically, we have to
基本上，我们必须
list all the attributes in
列出所有属性在~!@#$%^&*()
a particular type and remove
一特定类型并移除
the denied attributes
被拒绝的属性
and that's very cumbersome.
这非常麻烦。
We hope this problem can be solved.
我们希望这个问题能够得到解决。
Then there's also potential scalability issue
那么还有可能的可扩展性问题。
for the NAC-ABE approach.
对于NAC-ABE方法来说。
When the policies are very fine-grained,
当策略非常细粒度时，
there can be a large number
可能会有大量
of attributes that's
可能会有大量的属性，这些属性很难明确和处理。
difficult to specify and also handle.
很难明确和处理。
We need a very reliable repo implementation
我们需要一个非常可靠的仓库实现。
that can support high-speed,
能够支持高速，
reliable data and insertion.
能够支持高速，可靠的数据传输和插入。
In the second year we want to finish
在第二年我们想要完成
the implementation
的实施
and testing of the system,
和系统的测试，
and then we want to deploy
接下来我们想要部署
mGuard on the NDN testbed by connecting
接下来我们想要部署mGuard在NDN测试床上通过连接
the MD2K server to and subscribers
接下来我们想要部署mGuard在NDN测试床上通过连接到MD2K服务器并添加订阅者。这就是我要说的全部。
to the testbed. That's all for me.
接下来我们要把它部署到测试床上。我要说的就是这些。
>> Great. Thank you
>> 非常好。谢谢你。
very much for right at time there
感谢您准时到达。
are some nice questions
有一些不错的问题
in the Slack channel,
在Slack频道中，
so if you have time to
所以如果你有时间去
answer them over there,
请回答他们，在那边。
I think that would be great.
我认为那会很棒。
Let's move on to the next.
让我们继续下一个。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> It's my pleasure
>> 这是我的荣幸。
to introduce Susmit Shannigrahi.
介绍Susmit Shannigrahi。
I hope I got that close.
我希望我猜得很接近。
Who is a professor
谁是教授？
at Tennessee Tech University,
在田纳西科技大学，
directs to the next generation Internet lab
指向下一代互联网实验室。
there is research focuses on
该研究聚焦于
building tools and protocols that
构建工具和协议，以
facilitate big data management
促进大数据管理
and movement over the Internet.
和在互联网上的传输与流动。
He studies, designs, and builds
他研究、设计和构建
intelligent protocols for
智能协议用于
that next generation here.
下一代在这里。
Today assessment talk is on Hydra secure,
今天的评估讨论是关于Hydra安全的，
distributed and federated storage
分布式和联邦存储
for large and science data
对于大型和科学数据
and I directly again to black for questions,
我将直接再次向黑色提问，
and we'll try to leave a couple minutes.
我们会尽量留出几分钟。
If you can suspended at the end
如果你能在最后暂停一下
for some questions that we
对于我们可能有的一些问题，如果你能在最后暂停一下，可以回答它们。非常感谢。
can answer them. Thanks so much.
可以回答它们。非常感谢。
>> Thank you. Can you see my screen?
>> 谢谢。你能看到我的屏幕吗？
>> Yes, we can see it.
>> 是的，我们能看到你的屏幕。
>> Great. Good morning everyone.
>> 太好了。大家早上好。
This is a new NSF project
这是一个新的国家科学基金会项目。
that started last month, so it's brand new.
这个项目是上个月开始的，所以它是全新的。
But we have been working on this
但我们一直在进行这项工作
for last year or so.
大约在过去的一年里。
I'm going to present a Hydra.
我将要介绍一种叫做Hydra的东西。
It's a federated storage system over
它是一个联合存储系统，覆盖了
NDN and this is
NDN是这个~!@#$%^&*()
a collaborative effort
一项合作努力
between Tennessee take Clemson,
在田纳西州和克莱姆森大学之间的合作努力，FIU和UCLA也参与其中。
FIU, and UCLA.
佛罗里达国际大学（FIU）和加州大学洛杉矶分校（UCLA）。
These are the *** and then
~!@#$%^&*()
I don't know why the student
我不知道为什么那个学生
names didn't show up,
名字没有显示出来。
but I had been there.
但我已经去过那里了。
The goal for Hydra is to
Hydra的目标是
have really federated
已经实现了真正的联邦化
storage system over NDN.
存储系统在NDN上。
The motivation is, we
我们的动机是，我们
know at this point
我们现在知道的是，
that the large scientific data sets,
我们现在知道的是，大型科学数据集，
such as high-energy physics,
像高能物理学这样的领域，
as you've heard yesterday, in genomics,
像你昨天听到的，在基因组学领域，
they can really benefit from NDNs
他们确实可以从命名数据网络中获益。
named-based and location
基于名称和位置
transparent networking.
透明网络。
But to make that a reality,
但要实现这一点，
we need to make the data available first.
我们首先需要使数据可用。
How do we make the data available over NDN.
我们如何通过NDN使数据可用。
We have a couple of ways of doing it,
我们有几种方法可以做到这一点，
so we could have a stand alone repository.
因此我们可以拥有一个独立的存储库。
Like NDN repo,
像NDN存储库一样，
but that doesn't scale very well.
但这并不非常适合扩展。
Now, we could have file system interfaces,
现在，我们可以有文件系统接口，
as you heard from Katelyn stock yesterday.
正如你昨天从Katelyn Stock那里听到的。
But then the replication and
但随后的复制和~!@#$%^&*()
availability becomes user's responsibility.
可用性变成了用户的责任。
In this talk, we're going to talk about
在这次演讲中，我们将要讨论
federated repository
联邦仓库
that are also self-organizing.
它们还能自我组织。
The users, they can publish
用户们，他们可以发布
the data sets into these repositories
将数据集上传到这些存储库
and then forget about
然后就忘掉了
all the logistics of publishing data.
所有发布数据的后勤工作。
Logistics include replication,
物流包括复制，
access control.
访问控制。
If a node fails,
如果一个节点出现故障，
then failure recovery,
故障恢复，
all that is taken care of by Hydra.
这一切都由Hydra来处理。
For this project we use
这个项目我们使用~!@#$%^&*()
the genomics community as the driver.
基因组学社区作为驱动力。
What are the requirements
基因组学社区的需求是什么？
for the genomics community?
对基因组学社区来说？
This is going to be very generic.
这将会非常通用。
It's going to be the
这将会是
same for many scientific communities,
对许多科学界来说也是如此，
as at the first requirement is
根据第一个要求是
that storage system must support
该存储系统必须支持
very large data sets that can be anywhere
非常大的数据集，这些数据集可以位于任何地方
from terabytes to
从太字节到
petabytes and eventually exabytes.
太字节和最终艾字节。
Data publication mechanisms have to be
数据发布机制必须要
simple and then provide
简单然后提供
persistent storage at the file level.
持久化存储在文件级别上。
Unlike the original repository designs
与原始仓库设计不同
where we are storing NDN packets,
我们正在存储NDN数据包的地方，
Hydra is going to store files.
九头蛇将要存储文件。
Downloading object
下载对象
would be at the high level.
将处于高水平。
These communities are
这些社区将处于高水平，地理分布，
geographically distributed,
地理分布，
so the data sets are
所以数据集是
replicated for availability and
复制用于提高可用性和
then there's an option to optimize
那么就有一个优化的选项
the placement of data based
数据的放置基于
on where they are needed.
根据它们所需的地方进行放置。
Of course, NDN
当然，NDN
provides transparent data access.
提供透明的数据访问。
But we also need for
但我们也需要为
some of the genomics datasets,
一些基因组学数据集，
we need access control.
我们需要访问控制。
Because as you can imagine,
因为你可以想象，
genomics data can be privacy sensitive.
基因组数据可能涉及隐私敏感信息。
To follow up a little bit on
继续稍微跟进一下
what's available today for
今天有什么可用的
the genomics community,
基因组学界，
they need simple and
他们需要简单和安全的发表与获取
secure publication and access
安全的发布和访问
mechanisms and then have
机制，然后拥有
persistent and replicated data storege.
持久化和复制的数据存储。
The current options right
当前的选项正确
now it can go to a central repository,
现在它可以被发送到一个中央存储库，
NCBI or NHS and then tell them,
现在它可以被发送到一个中央存储库，比如NCBI或NHS，然后告诉他们，我需要发布这些数据。
I need to publish this data
我需要发布这些数据
will you do that for me?
你会帮我做那件事吗？
They might say, "Okay I'll publish your data,
他们可能会说：“好的，我会发布你的数据，
but it might take a few months to do that."
但这可能需要几个月的时间来完成。
Or they might say, this data is
或者他们可能会说，这些数据是
not in our interest to publish,
所以我们不会发布那些数据。
so we're not going to take that data.
所以我们不会采取那些数据。
Then if the second thing happens,
那么如果第二件事发生了，
then scientists have the result
那么科学家们就有了结果
to add her publication.
添加她的出版物。
It might be an HTTP web server,
它可能是一个HTTP网络服务器，
it can be a scientist's personal webpage,
它可能是一个科学家的个人网页，
FTP server, but then it becomes very ad hoc
FTP服务器，但随后它变得非常特定临时。
and then finding and utilizing
然后找到并利用
the data becomes very difficult.
然后找到并利用这些数据变得非常困难。
Now, when the scientists
现在，当科学家们
wonder run in workflow,
they have to specify wonders about the operation of workflows,
they have to specify
他们必须指定
which data sets they want to use,
他们必须指定要使用哪些数据集，
and the problem with
和问题有关
ad hoc publication is it
临时出版物是这样的
things become hard-coded
事情变得硬编码
into those workloads.
进入那些工作负载中。
If anything needs to change,
如果有什么需要改变，
the whole workflow needs to change
整个工作流程需要改变。
and which can be very tedious.
这可能会非常乏味。
The other thing we noted
我们还注意到了其他事情。
that Cloud storage is expensive.
我们还注意到了其他事情。云存储是昂贵的。我们潜在可以考虑
We could potentially put
我们潜在可以考虑将所有数据放入云端并完成此事。
all the data into the Cloud and be done.
我们可以考虑把所有数据放到云端并完成这件事。
But it's not cheap
但这并不便宜。
to store that amount of data in the Cloud.
将那么多数据存储在云端。
But storage is also
但存储也是
available at various institutes,
在各个研究所也不容易获得，
but they cannot be easily
但它们并不容易
utilizable or federated.
可利用的或联合的。
Each institute operates in their silos and
各个研究所都在各自的孤立中运作着，
provides access to the local researchers,
为当地研究人员提供了访问权限，
which is obviously not very efficient,
显然这样做效率并不高。
and also limits the capacity
并且也限制了容量
that they can have.
它们可以拥有的。
Data security is currently very challenging.
数据安全目前非常具有挑战性。
Access control is tied to
访问控制与~!@#$%^&*()相关联。
a specific publication system.
一个特定的发布系统。
If it's HTTP,
如果是HTTP，
it uses one-third of access control,
它使用了三分之一的访问控制，
if it's S bearer or FTP,
如果是S承载或者FTP，
it might be different.
它可能会有所不同。
Then there's a huge
那么就有一个巨大的
manual component to all of these.
所有这些都有一个手动的组成部分。
There's user credential setups,
用户凭证设置，
role management, role assignment,
角色管理，角色分配，
and then if a user leaves,
然后如果一个用户离开，
the credentials need to be updated.
凭证需要更新。
Then finally, the data delivery,
然后最后，数据传递，
even when it's encrypted,
即使数据被加密，
it's over individual
它结束了，个人的
and separate secure channels.
和单独的安全通道。
There is no inherent security to the data.
数据本身并没有内在的安全性。
It's all tied to
它全都与...有关联
either the channels
它全都与...有关联，或者是频道
or individual encryptions.
或者是个人加密。
If a lab has five students and we want
如果一个实验室有五名学生，我们想要
to provide personalized security
为每个人提供个性化的安全保护
for each of them,
为他们每个人，
it becomes very difficult.
它变得非常困难。
Either you encrypt the data five times,
或者你将数据加密五次，
or you encrypt once,
或者你将数据加密一次，
you keep the key to the PI,
你将密钥保留给PI，
and then the PI decides
然后PI决定如何操作
how to secure the data,
如何保护数据，
which again, is not very efficient.
这又一次效率不高。
At a very high level,
在一个非常高的层面上，
this is what Hydra is.
这就是Hydra是什么。
It's a federated storage system in
它是一个联合存储系统，在
the network over NDN,
它是通过NDN网络进行的，
sorry, it's a set of repo nodes.
很抱歉，这是一组仓库节点。
It utilizes
它利用
every level storage at
它利用每个层级的存储在
different organizations.
不同的组织。
We're thinking unlike Cassandra or
我们的想法不像Cassandra或者
distributed databases which are
分布式数据库，它们是
under single management.
在单一管理之下。
These are at different institutes
这些位于不同的研究所。
managed by different people.
这些由不同的人管理。
But once you install Hydra,
但一旦你安装了Hydra，
it becomes a self-organizing system.
它就变成了一个自组织系统。
Then once the data is published,
那么一旦数据被发布，
it uses Anycast,
它使用了Anycast，
NDN's default Anycast mechanism
NDN默认的Anycast机制
or data access.
或数据访问。
The replication also happens automatically.
复制也会自动进行。
Right now, the default degree
现在，默认的复制程度是三。
of replication is three.
的复制程度是三。
But that can be tune
但这可以根据社区的需要进行调整。
based on what is needed by the community.
根据社区的需要。
Then once the data is replicated,
那么一旦数据被复制之后，
it can be requested by anyone.
它可以被任何人请求。
The Hydra also handles failure transparently.
九头蛇还能透明处理失败。
If a node fails,
如果一个节点出现故障，
data is automatically replicated to another.
数据会自动复制到另一个节点。
Then it maintains, if possible,
然后它会尽可能地维护，
the desired degree of replication.
保持所需的复制程度。
For security, we are planning to
为了安全起见，我们正计划
use NDN's name based trust schemas,
使用NDN的基于名称的信任模式，
and both traditional PKI
和传统的公钥基础设施(PKI)
and attribute-based access control.
与基于属性的访问控制相比较。
The other aspect is
另一个方面是
findability of this data,
数据的可查找性，
so we are planning to provide
所以我们正计划提供
a uniform name based interface for all data.
一个统一的基于名称的接口用于所有数据。
Instead of the scientists finding out whether
科学家们是否发现了
the data comes from a legacy
数据来自一个遗留系统
FTP or HTTP storage,
FTP或HTTP存储，
they are all going to go through Hydra.
它们都将通过Hydra进行处理。
It provides them a unified namespace.
它为它们提供了一个统一的命名空间。
Then Hydra takes care of getting the data
然后Hydra负责获取数据
for them and then solving it back to them.
为他们解决问题然后再回传给他们。
There's an intermediate
存在一个中间过程在为他们解决问题然后再回传给他们和translation that happens之间。
translation that happens.
发生的翻译过程。
If the data is useful for many people,
如果这些数据对许多人有用，
then it potentially can upload the data,
那么它有可能上传这些数据，
but that's for future work.
但那是未来的工作。
This is a little bit more detailed view
这是一个稍微详细一点的视图。
of how Hydra works.
这是 Hydra 如何工作的一个稍微详细一点的视图。在左边你有出版商 A
On the left you have publisher A
在左边你有出版商 A
that sends a publication request
向云端发送一份出版请求
to the Cloud,
向云端，
which is Hydra, and then
它是九头蛇，然后
that request goes to
该请求被发送至
a repo that's closest to the publisher.
距离发布者最近的一个仓库。
The publisher looks at the trust schema,
发布者查看信任模式，
does access control,
进行访问控制，
and then retrieves
然后检索
the file from the publisher.
出版商提供的文件。
Then at that point,
那么在那个时候，
it generates a notification
它会生成一个通知
to the other nodes in the system.
向系统中的其他节点发送。
The notification goes out.
通知已经发出。
Everyone knows that a new file has come in.
大家都知道新文件已经送来了。
We're going to talk about
我们将要讨论
how they are replicated.
它们是如何复制的。
But depending on if
但这取决于是否
they get the data from that,
他们从那里获取数据。
the first contacted node and
他们首先接触的节点并且
then replicate into their repo.
然后复制到他们的代码库中。
At the top, you've
在顶部，你已经~!@#$%^&*()
seen ray that's in a archway.
在拱门里看到了那道光。
That's the interface with
那是与...的接口。
the existing data repositories.
那是与现有数据仓库的接口。
Your request comes in
您的请求已收到。
from user A or user B on the right.
来自用户A或用户B的右侧。
If the data is already not in Hydra,
如果数据已经不在Hydra中，
the Hydra goes out and
如果数据已经不在Hydra中，Hydra就会出去并且
then get the data from
去获取数据来自
the existing repository.
现有的仓库。
In the middle, Hydra uses sync SVS,
在中间，Hydra使用同步状态向量同步(SVS)，
a State Vector Sync to keep
保持状态向量同步
the global state consistent
保持全局状态一致
among the different repositories.
在不同的仓库之间。
Speaking a little bit about the design,
谈一谈设计方面的事情，
we assume a few things here.
我们在这里假设了一些事情。
We assume that all the nodes are equal.
我们假设所有节点是平等的。
There is no single point of control.
没有单一的控制点。
As I said, it replicates
正如我所说，它进行复制
data at the file granularity.
数据以文件粒度存在。
Files are immutable just like NDN.
文件就像NDN一样是不可变的。
The repo only handles insertion and deletion.
该代码库只处理插入和删除操作。
There's not update. Then I
该代码库没有更新。然后我
think this is the most
我认为这是最重要的Hydra的一个方面，
important aspect of Hydra,
的一个重要方面，
is that each node makes
是每个节点都做出
local decisions about which file
本地决策关于哪个文件
they want to replicate.
他们想要复制。
We do this by
我们通过这样做来
creating a numerical value
我们通过这样做来创造一个数值，that we call favor.
that we call favor.
我们称之为“好感度”。
Each node announces a favor
每个节点宣告一个“好感度”。
to the whole system saying that this is
对整个系统宣称这是
how likely I am to
多大可能我会
replicate a new file that would come in.
复制一个新进来的文件。
Then Hydra is not responsible
那么九头蛇就不负责任了。
for file confidentiality.
为了文件的保密性。
It does access control.
它进行访问控制。
But if file confidentiality is needed,
但如果需要文件保密，
the user needs to
用户需要
encrypt and upload that code.
加密并上传那段代码。
Then for now at the initial stage,
那么现在在初始阶段，
we are assuming there is no compromise now,
我们现在假设没有妥协，
but that assumption with
但那种假设将会在未来发生改变。
change in the future.
将来会发生改变。
The basic building block for Hydra is files.
Hydra的基本构建块是文件。
Users, it's just a BLOB
用户，它只是一个二进制大对象（BLOB）。
of data identified by a name.
对于数据来说，它是由一个名称来识别的。
The data publisher can insert a file.
数据发布者可以插入一个文件。
Biology SRA followed by the SRA ID,
生物学SRA后面跟着SRA编号，
and that's a genome sequence.
这是一个基因组序列。
The consumer can send
消费者可以发送
an NDN interest through the system.
消费者可以通过系统发送一个NDN兴趣。
It says slash Hydra slash fetch,
它表示“/Hydra/fetch”，
followed by that name and gets the data back.
它跟随那个名称并获取数据返回。
For this work we are using
我们在这项工作中使用
the established naming scheme
我们在这项工作中使用的既定命名方案
that has already been
已经被设定
created by the community.
由社区创建。
We just took it and translated
我们只是拿来并翻译了它。
that into NDN naming scheme.
将其转换为NDN命名方案。
The basic operations are insertion deletion.
基本操作是插入删除。
Again, just like getting the data,
再次，就像获取数据一样，
you send a command to the repo prefix,
您向仓库前缀发送了一个命令，
followed by the actual data.
接着是实际的数据。
Then the data consumers,
接着是数据消费者，
they turn interest directly
他们直接转变为兴趣。
to Hydra to get the data.
前往九头蛇以获取数据。
Here is what happens on publication.
这是发表时所发生的事情。
The app on the right,
应用程序在右边，
it publishes the data.
它发布了数据。
It contracts a node that's closest to it,
它收缩了一个离它最近的节点，
and then at that point,
然后在那时，
the node generates a group message that goes
节点生成一个群发消息，该消息会发送
to everyone else to Vector Sync.
to everyone else to Vector Sync. 节点生成一个群发消息，该消息会发送给其他所有人以进行向量同步。在那时，每个人都知道有
At that point, everyone knows that there is
一个新文件他们可能需要复制。
a new file they might need to replicate.
他们可能需要复制的一个新文件。
Hydra also maintains a Global View.
九头蛇还维护着一个全球视角。
The group message is
群组消息是
essentially trying to exchange
本质上是在尝试交流
that Global View and update it.
更新全球视角。
On the right you'd see it has a bunch of
在右边你会看到它有一堆~!@#$%^&*()
nodes and each node has individual favors.
节点都有各自的偏好设置。
Whenever a new file comes in,
每当有新文件进来时，
this message is exchanged.
这条信息被交换了。
Then everyone knows that what are
Then everyone knows what are ~!@#$%^&*()
the top three or top five nodes
前三名或前五名的节点
are that can potentially
有潜力的是可以
replicate these files.
复制这些文件。
As I said, nodes are self-organizing.
正如我所说，节点是自组织的。
The file insertion would be file comes in.
文件插入将会执行。
It consults the Global View,
它查询全局视图，
and it chooses three to six nodes
并且它选择三到六个节点
depending on that Global View.
根据那个全局视图。
Then once the notification goes in,
那么一旦通知发出去之后，
everyone knows that they're the next
每个人都知道他们是下一个。
to copy that file or replicate the file.
复制那个文件或者复制该文件。
On the left at bottom,
在左下角，
you'll see on list and backup list.
你会在列表和备份列表上看到。
On list is it's already on that node,
列表上已经有那个节点了。
and then the backup list is
然后是备份列表。
where the replication should happen next.
接下来应该进行复制的地方。
This is that it's on the backup list and it's
这就是它在备份列表上的情况，并且它是
the first on the backup list that
这就是它在备份列表上的情况，并且它是备份列表中的第一个，
starts to replicate the file from F,
开始从F复制文件，
and then B does it next.
然后B接着做。
Then eventually, when
然后最终，当
three copies are achieved,
三份副本被获得后，
then the replication stops.
副本复制就会停止。
If a node crashes,
如果一个节点崩溃了，
some of the other nodes might
其他一些节点可能会
notice that a node has failed,
注意到一个节点已经失败，
and then it might send out
然后它可能会发送出去
a notification saying that node D has failed.
一个通知显示节点D已经失败。
At that point,
在那时候，
again, and the nodes are
再次，节点们是
going to console the backup list.
将要去控制台查看备份列表。
The node G is the
节点G是
first one on the backup list so
所以是备份列表中的第一个
it takes that five replicates
它需要那五个副本
in its own storage,
在它自己的存储中，
and then we have again,
然后我们再次拥有，
replication degree of three.
复制度为三。
Deletion is simple.
删除很简单。
Only the publisher can
只有发布者可以
delete the file from the repo.
从仓库中删除文件。
It sends to command
它发送了一个命令
to the repo saying that delete this file,
向仓库发送了一条命令，说要删除这个文件，
and then that message goes
然后那条消息就发出去了。
across everyone who has that file deletes.
每个拥有那个文件的人都将其删除了。
Then file fetching is pretty simple in NDN.
在NDN中，获取文件变得非常简单。
You just send the request if
您只需发送请求即可，如果
that particular node does
该特定节点确实这样做了
not have the content.
没有内容。
When you talk about global view,
当你谈论全球视角时，
we're not talking about the actual data,
我们不是在谈论实际的数据，
we're talking about metadata.
我们在谈论的是元数据。
But the actual data, not all nodes would
但实际数据，并不是所有节点都会
have the same all data sets.
并不是所有数据集都会相同。
If the request comes into F
如果请求进入了F
and F has the data,
如果F中有数据，
it returns the data.
它会返回数据。
But if it doesn't have it,
但如果它没有的话，
it sends back a forwarding hint
它会发送回一个转发提示
to a node that has the data,
向拥有数据的节点，
and then the app follows that hint
然后应用程序根据那个提示进行操作
and gets the data from another node.
并从另一个节点获取数据。
In this example, it might be D or A, or B.
在这个例子中，可能是D或者A，或者是B。
>> Personally, I just want to give you
>> 个人来说，我只是想给你
a one minute warning here.
还有一分钟的警告。
We're getting close to end.
我们快要结束了。
>> Yes, I'm almost done. Thank you.
是的，我快要结束了。谢谢。
The other parts of
其他部分
the project is NR-archway,
项目名为NR-archway，
as I was mentioning that
正如我之前提到的那样
currently the files,
当前的文件，
they have diverse names, metadata standards.
它们具有多样的名称、元数据标准。
The problem becomes it
问题变成了它
cannot find the data sets,
如果你找不到数据集，
and if you cannot find the datasets,
那么你就无法使用
them in the scientific workflows.
那么你就无法在科学工作流中使用它们。The archway acts as a gateway to all data.
The archway acts as a gateway to all data.
拱门充当了通往所有数据的门户。
It converts to NDN data as needed.
它根据需要转换为NDN数据。
User need not know the publication specifics.
用户无需了解出版的具体细节。
If it's over NDN,
如果是通过NDN，
if it's over HTTP,
如果是通过HTTP，
if it is over FTP or SFTP or something else.
如果是通过FTP、SFTP或其他方式。
It does it through a name conversion catalog
它是通过名称转换目录来实现的。
and then creating
然后创建
an interface to
一个界面用于
HTTP or FTP existing repositories.
HTTP或FTP现有的仓库。
The security we're assuming for now,
我们目前所假设的安全性，
there is going to be a central trust anchor,
将会有一个中央信任锚点，
the network operating center
网络运营中心
that's going to issue
将要发放
the certificates to individual
即将发放给个人的证书
nodes and the users.
节点和用户。
Then once you have the attributes
那么一旦你有了属性
and the certificates,
和证书，
then you can create name based
然后你可以创建基于名称的
access control both traditional
传统的访问控制
and attribute-based name control.
和基于属性的名称控制。
Attribute-based encryption is what
基于属性的加密是我们将用于访问控制的一种方式。
we're going to use for access control.
我们将用于访问控制。
Then the final part is testing.
然后最后一个部分是测试。
We are working with Fabric to
我们正在与Fabric合作，以
deploy this on Fabric.
部署在Fabric上。
The goal is to have
目标是要
the Hydra on Fabric and then we'll
我们将在Fabric上使用Hydra，然后我们将
have workflows that will
有将要运行的工作流程，它们将会
be deployed on different
部署在不同的
cloud computing platforms.
云计算平台上。
It can be AWS,
它可以是AWS，
it can be PRP,
它可以是PRP，
the Pacific Research Platform
太平洋研究平台
, Open Science Grid.
, 开放科学网格。
We're going to simulate
我们将要模拟
10 to1000 simulated users from
10到1000个模拟用户从
these workflows and get
这些工作流程并获取
the data out of Hydra.
这些数据从Hydra中获取。
That way we will get a real feel of
这样我们将真正感受到
how the system is behaving
系统的运行情况
if we need any optimization,
如果我们需要进行任何优化，
how the system scales, and so on.
系统如何扩展等问题。
To conclude, so currently
总结一下，所以目前
the data publication is very
散乱的，且可发现性非常差。
The Hydra tries to address that.
九头蛇试图解决这个问题。
There are storage at various institutes.
各个研究所都有存储设施。
They are not sufficient for
它们不足以满足
everything that the scientists want to do.
they are not enough to satisfy everything that the scientists want to do.
If we could federate them,
如果我们能将它们联合起来，
they can support large-scale genomics
它们可以支持大规模基因组学研究。
and then security currently
并且目前的安全性
is difficult to configure.
难以配置。
Hydra addresses all this by creating
Hydra通过创建来解决所有这些问题
a loosely coupled and
一个松散耦合的
self-organization federated storage system.
自组织联邦存储系统。
Thank you and I'll take
谢谢，我会接受
any questions you might have on Slack.
如果你有任何问题，可以在Slack上提问。
>> Thanks, Susmit. In the interest of time,
>> 谢谢，Susmit。为了节省时间，
let's direct the questions to
让我们将问题直接提给
Slack and we'll get to the next speaker.
让我们将问题直接提给Slack，然后我们将转向下一位发言者。
There's already a few in
已经有一些了
the Slack discussion
Slack讨论
for this particular paper.
对于这篇特定的论文。
Our next speaker is Tianyuan Yu from UCLA,
我们下一位演讲者是来自加州大学洛杉矶分校的余天元。
who is a PhD candidate in
他是一名博士研究生，在
the computer science department under
他是一名博士研究生，在计算机科学系，在教授的指导下。
the supervision of Professor.
在李壮教授的指导下。
Professor Li Zhuang.
李壮教授。
His main research interests
他的主要研究兴趣
are named data networking,
命名数据网络，
IoT and network security.
物联网和网络安全。
He's also contributing to
他也在为此做出贡献。
the development of NDN,
NDN的发展，
IoT and security bootstrapping.
物联网和安全引导。
That's what I think he's going
我认为他要去的是
to talk about today.
我认为他要去的是今天要讨论的话题。The title of the talk is,
The title of the talk is,
The title of the talk is, ~!@#$%^&*()
"Bootstrapping Remote NDN Entity,
"引导远程NDN实体，
Leveraging Existing
利用现有的
Authentications." Thank you.
认证。谢谢。
>> Can people see my screen?
>> 人们能看到我的屏幕吗？
>> Yes, we can.
>> 是的，我们能看到。
>> Yeah, thank you. Hi, everyone.
>> 是的，谢谢你。大家好。
Glad to be here at the NDN com.
很高兴来到NDN公司。
Today, my presentation
今天，我的演讲
we'll focus on how we can
我们将专注于我们如何能够
bootstrap remote and the entities so
引导远程以及相关实体。
we can meet your NDN neighbors from far.
我们可以远距离遇见你的NDN邻居。
We know NDN claims data are secured
我们知道NDN声称数据是安全的
saying in the network we have
在网络中我们有
producers, we have consumers.
生产者，我们有消费者。
But those producers and consumers need
但是那些生产者和消费者需要
some bootstrappings
一些自举程序
to actually secure communications.
为了确保通信的安全。
We know producers use
我们知道生产者使用
their private key to sign
他们的私钥进行签名
the ddata and the consumer can
使用生产者的公钥来验证数据，消费者可以
use producer's public key to verify the data.
使用生产者的公钥来验证数据。
But the question is,
但问题是，
where are the keys?
钥匙在哪里？
Someone has to configure
有人必须进行配置
the keys into those entities.
因此，每个实体都需要获取这些密钥。
Therefore, each entity need to obtain
these keys to authenticate their security credentials.
their security credentials
他们的安全凭证
from these bootstrapping process.
从这个引导过程中。
Before I talk about how we can get
在我讲述我们如何能够获得
those security credentials
那些安全凭证
into the entities,
进入实体中，
I want to go back a little bit to talk about
我想稍微回溯一下，谈谈
what are the terminologies we
我们将在这个过程中使用的术语是什么？
will use in this process.
我们将在这个过程中使用。
We still have this NDN network.
我们仍然有这个NDN网络。
Then we say the authority
那么我们说权威
of the network system
的网络系统
and create a trust anchor,
并创建一个信任锚点，
we say T. This
我们说T。这
authority can be authority from real world,
权威可以是现实世界中的权威，
say the authority of
权威可以是
an organizations or smart home or
一个组织或者智能家居或者
the active project we
正在进行的项目我们
saw from the earlier presentation
来自早先演示的内容
is like mGuard and the Hydra.
就像mGuard和Hydra一样。
Then all of the entities
那么所有的实体
under the same trust anchor,
在同一个信任锚下，
which means they trust
这意味着他们信任
the same self certificate.
同一个自签名证书。
Those in the entities can make a trust zone.
实体中的成员可以创建一个信任区域。
Then the owner of this trust anchor T,
然后这个信任锚点T的所有者，
we refer this as
我们将这称为
the controller of the trust zone.
我们将这称为信任区域的控制器。Then with this terminology,
Then with this terminology,
那么有了这个术语，
we can say bootstrapping a new entity
我们可以说是自举一个新实体。
E_new is really bootstrapping
E_new确实是在自举。
these E_new into this trust zone.
将这些E_new纳入这个信任区域。
This E_new must have
这些E_new必须具备
a name either obtained on its
一个它本身获得的名字
own or otherwise assigned
拥有或以其他方式被分配
by this trust of controller,.
被该控制器信任。
Then E_new must have its trust anchor,
那么E_new必须有它的信任锚点，
say this T, and
那么T，以及
its own certificate and the trust policies.
它自己的证书和信任策略。
We refer this process
我们将这个过程称为安全引导。
After security bootstrapping we
在安全引导之后，我们
can answer a few questions.
可以回答几个问题。
First, for our entity, who are you?
首先，对于我们的实体来说，你是谁？
This entity will have a name,
这个实体将会有一个名字，
say slash alice slash lamp.
说斜杠爱丽丝斜杠灯。
Then we can have the security credentials to
然后我们可以拥有安全凭证来
prove the identity of this alice lamp.
证明这个爱丽丝灯的身份。
knows who to trust
知道该信任谁
under the same trust anchor.
在同一个信任锚下。
We can answer the questions
我们可以回答这些问题。
that what are your cross relations?
那么你们的交叉关系是什么？
But let's think about how we
但让我们想想我们如何~!@#$%^&*()
can actually say realise such a process.
可以实际上实现这样一个过程。
What are the required steps?
需要遵循哪些必要步骤？
First, we have controllers
首先，我们有控制器。
and the E_new in this field.
以及这个领域中的E_new。
But actually as the first step
但实际上作为第一步
the trust zone controller
信任区域控制器
needs to authenticate E_new.
它需要对E_new进行身份验证。
It wants to make sure
它想要确保
the remote priority is transversing.
远程优先级正在转换。
Then E_new to authenticate
则使用E_new进行认证
the trust zone controller also,
信任区域控制器也是如此，
because it wants to accept
因为它想要接受
that controller to be its authority.
因为它想要接受那个控制器作为它的权威。After this mutual authentication achieved,
After this mutual authentication achieved,
在实现了这种相互认证之后，
the controller can install
控制器可以安装
the security components which
安全组件包括
contains the certificate,
包含证书，
the trust policy and trust
信任策略和信任
anchors into this E_new.
锚定到这个 E_new 中。
Given the such important process,
鉴于这一重要过程，
there must be some works in this field.
在这个领域一定有一些研究工作。
Among all the existing works we have NDNCERT.
在我们现有的作品中，我们有NDNCERT。
But NDNCERT only issues certificate,
但NDNCERT只负责颁发证书，
leaving the authentication methods,
离开认证方法，
which is the first step
离开认证方法，which is the first step as a need to be filled in.
as a need to be filled in.
作为需要填补的一项需求。
We have this Data-Centric Toolkit
我们有这个以数据为中心的工具包，
shortened as DCT,
缩写为DCT，
which is this unit is actually in paper,
这个单元实际上是在纸上的，
which provides command-line tools
它提供了命令行工具。
to generate a security bundle
生成安全包
and the user for
和用户为了
the out-of-band install
带外安装
this bundle into the E_new.
将这个包装束集成到E_new中。
The mutual authentication is done through
双方通过相互认证来完成。
this some kind of
这是某种类型的
locally physically connected environment.
本地物理连接环境。
But however, we need to
但是，我们需要
solve a new problem now,
解决一个新问题，
which is remote bootstrapping.
这就是远程引导。
We can also see
我们也可以看到
from the previous presentation,
从之前的演示来看，
this remote bootstrapping is
这种远程引导是
also needed by Hydra.
也是九头蛇所需要的。
We can see the important part
我们可以看到重要的部分
is the mutual authentication.
是相互认证。
That authentication
是认证。
needs some existing facts to verify.
需要一些现有的事实来进行验证。
We need to answer the questions that
我们需要回答那些问题，
where are the existing facts come from?
现有的事实是从哪里来的？
However, the answers depends
然而，答案取决于
on specific use case scenarios.
在特定的使用案例场景中。
Therefore we develop
因此我们开发了
specific security bootstrapping process
特定的安全引导过程
on this remote case.
在这个远程案例中。
We say this E_new is
我们称这个E_new为
remote and the trusted controller can only
远程和可信控制器只能
reach remote E_new over
the current unsecure TCP/IP connectivity.
current unsecure TCP/IP connectivity.
当前不安全的TCP/IP连接。
Then we will do
然后我们将会进行
that mutual authentication first,
然后我们将会进行那个相互认证首先，
then install the security components.
然后安装安全组件。
To achieve this mutual authentication
为了实现这种相互认证
between the controller and the E_new,
在控制器和E_new之间，
first look at the OPrah arc.
首先看一下OPrah弧。
Our controller authenticate E_new.
我们的控制器认证了E_new。
I'm looking through the interaction of
我正在查看交互作用
leveraging existing authentication solutions.
利用现有的身份验证解决方案。
Fortunately, there are many of
幸运的是，有很多利用现有的身份验证解决方案来保护它们在当前互联网中的。
them in current Internet.
它们在当前互联网中。
We have the security authorities
我们有安全机构
which issues certificates with
颁发证书的相关问题
with DNS name,
关于DNS名称，
then we also have DNSSEC
然后我们还有DNSSEC
accompanied with the finger system
伴随着指法系统
to provide authentication to DNS names.
提供对DNS名称的认证。
Also if you are a user with the password,
如果你是拥有密码的用户，
you can use some technologies
你可以使用一些技术
like Single- Sign- On
像单点登录
to authenticate yourself in
在...中认证自己
the today's web system.
今天的网络系统。
Now let's think about there are
现在让我们思考这里有
such authentication system here,
这样的认证系统在这里，
in today's internet, and that's
在当今的互联网中，这就是
authentication system authenticate
认证系统进行身份验证
this remote E_new.
这是新遥控器。
Then if the controller
那么如果是遥控器
asked this authentication system,
询问了这个认证系统，
then controller can derive
然后控制器可以推导出
authentication through this remote E_new.
通过这个远程E_new进行认证。
We can get that first OPrah arc done.
我们可以完成第一个OPrah弧段的工作。
Assuming E_new is NDN app
假设E_new是NDN应用。
running on remote hosts H,
运行在远程主机H上，
then the CA authenticate
然后CA进行认证
this remote host by issuing SSL certificate.
然后通过颁发SSL证书对这个远程主机进行认证。
Then Trust Zone Controller
接着是信任区域控制器
can authenticate E_new which
可以认证 E_new 的是
is the NDN app here,
the NDN app is here, ~!@#$%^&*()
if the DNS name of the remote host is
如果远程主机的DNS名称是
authenticated device A
认证设备A
with the SSL Certificate.
带有SSL证书。
Then we have got the OPrah arc down,
然后我们就完成了OPrah弧线的部分，
but what about the
但是关于那个
[inaudible] or
~!@#$%^&*()
E-new authenticated controller.
新认证的控制器。
The controller can put
新认证的控制器可以放置
the NDN app implementation code on GitHub
GitHub上的NDN应用实现代码
with the trust anchor app pre-embedded.
带有预嵌入的信任锚点应用程序。
Then someone say user,
然后有人说用户，
can download this code
可以下载这段代码
from sources like GitHub,
从GitHub这样的来源下载，
then the trusted controller is authenticated
然后对可信控制器进行身份验证
through Built-in
通过内置
during this software distribution
在这次软件分发期间
with the trust anchor embedded.
在这次软件分发期间，我们将这个方向应用到Hydra，并嵌入了信任锚点。
We will apply this direction to Hydra.
我们将这个方向应用到Hydra。
You can see from the previous
您可以从之前看到
presentation, in Hydra,
演示，在九头蛇，
different organizations who have contributed
不同组织所做的贡献
file servers and ensure data and
文件服务器并确保数据和
users from different organizations need to
不同组织的用户需要
install the Hydra app
安装Hydra应用程序
or they contributed a file server.
或者他们贡献了一个文件服务器。
Then the Hydra Network Operating Center
那么九头蛇网络运营中心
will serve as
将作为
the trust zone controller
信任区域控制器
for a namespace slash hydra.
对于命名空间/海德拉。
We can see here,
我们可以在这里看到，
the Hydra app running on
我们可以在这里看到，Hydra应用程序正在运行在
those remote file servers need
这些远程文件服务器需要
authentications as
这些远程文件服务器需要认证作为安全引导的要求。
the requirements of security bootstrapping.
安全引导的要求。
We have this Hydra app
我们有这个Hydra应用程序
running on remote host,
运行在远程主机上，
and this remote host has DNS name,
这个远程主机拥有DNS名称，
the bruins.cs.ucla.edu, and
这个远程主机的DNS名称是bruins.cs.ucla.edu，而且
UCLA's CA InCommon will authenticate
加州大学洛杉矶分校的CA InCommon将进行身份验证
the DNS name by issuing SSL Certificate.
CA InCommon at the University of California, Los Angeles will perform identity authentication, 在这种情况下，我们可以通过颁发SSL证书来查看DNS名称。
In this case, we can view
在这种情况下，我们可以查看
this SSL Certificates from this IP work,
这个IP的SSL证书工作正常，
as the existing authentication that we
可以用来启动Hydra应用的现有认证。
can utilize to bootstrap the Hydra app.
可以用于引导Hydra应用程序的启动。
We know also Incommon CA
我们也知道Incommon CA。
issued SSL certificate to the file server,
颁发了SSL证书给文件服务器，
then the Hydra NOC on the other hand,
则另一方面，Hydra NOC，
will trust this InCommon CA out of them,
将会信任这个InCommon CA，
by downloading InCommon CA Certificate
通过下载InCommon CA证书
from a trusted URL.
从一个可信的网址下载。
Then Hydra NOC thereby can authenticate all
然后 Hydra NOC 因此可以对所有进行身份验证
InCommon authenticated
InCommon 认证
host identifiers like Bruins.
像Bruins这样的主机标识符。
Thereby, it can authenticate
因此，它可以进行身份验证
the Hydra app instances
Hydra 应用实例
installed on these remote hosts.
安装在这些远程主机上。
Then on the order of the reaction,
那么在反应的顺序上，
as we mentioned earlier,
正如我们之前提到的，
the Hydra app will authenticate
Hydra应用程序将进行身份验证
Hydra NOC at
Hydra网络运营中心位于
the application installation time.
应用程序安装时间。
Hydra NOC puts the trust anchor
Hydra NOC 将信任锚
into the Hydra app implementation codes,
进入 Hydra 应用程序实现代码中，
and the user of Hydra app,
和 Hydra 应用程序的用户，
will download this code with
将会下载这段代码与
the pre-embedded trust anchor
预嵌入的信任锚点
and initial trust policies.
和初始信任策略。
However, the user authenticated
但是，用户已通过身份验证
application package on offence,
应用程序包含违规内容，
but however, this application package
但是，这个应用程序包
should be fetched from transmitter source.
应该从传输源获取。
If the Hydra app put
如果Hydra应用程序放置在~!@#$%^&*()
the code at the GitHub link,
代码位于GitHub链接中，
then users say Alice must obtain
然后用户说Alice必须获得
this URL from trusted channels,
这个来自可信渠道的URL，
to ensure she is
确保她是
fetching the correct package.
获取正确的包裹。
Now we have the mutual authentication,
现在我们有了双向认证，
the two arcs done,
完成了两个弧线，
let's talk about how we
让我们谈谈我们如何
can install this equipment components.
可以安装这些设备组件。
Before we talk about
在我们讨论之前
all the crypto materials like
所有加密材料，例如
certificates and permanent public keys,
证书和永久性公钥，
this NDN the entities Hydra app,
这个NDN实体Hydra应用程序，
should have a label first.
应该首先有一个标签。
In Hydra use case,
在Hydra用例中，
these E_new name has
这些E_new名称具有
the application prefix and the unique suffix.
应用程序前缀和唯一后缀。
The application prefix,
应用程序前缀，
can come from the trust anchor,
可以来源于信任锚点，
because we know the trust anchor
因为我们知道信任锚点
Then we always obtain
那么我们总是能够获得
its application prefix from it.
它的应用前缀。
But the unique suffix here needs assignment.
但这里的唯一后缀需要分配。
The remote host who is running a Hydra app,
正在运行Hydra应用程序的远程主机，
already has a name,
已经有一个名称，
this is DNS name.
这是DNS名称。
But in this case,
但在这种情况下，
we want to give this Hydra app a new name,
我们想要给这款Hydra应用起一个新名字，
which is a name under hydra's context.
我们想要给这款Hydra应用起一个新名字，它应该与Hydra的背景相符。
Solution could be after
解决方案可能是之后的
we apply this application prefix,
我们应用这个应用程序前缀，
we adopt a DNS name from
我们采用一个DNS名称来自
the remote host as the suffix assignment.
我们采用一个DNS名称来自远程主机作为后缀分配。
The entity name will
实体名称将会
be /hydra/bruins.cs.ucla.edu.
实体名称将会是/hydra/bruins.cs.ucla.edu。
Optionally Alice can still decide
如果愿意，Alice仍然可以决定
a new identifier that
适应九头蛇情境的新标识符。
fit into hydra's context.
适应九头蛇情境。
Now, we have the mutual authentication,
现在，我们拥有了相互认证，
we have the trust anchor
我们拥有了信任锚
and mutual trust policy installed,
和已安装的相互信任策略，
we obtain the name by adopting the DNS name
我们通过采用DNS名称来获取名字。
and append a after
和在后面追加一个a
the application prefix which
应用程序前缀，它
is coming from the trust anchor,
来自信任锚点，
but now here we still need certificate.
但现在我们仍然需要证书。
The Hydra app,
海德拉应用程序，
will use the NDNCERT protocol
将使用NDNCERT协议
to apply the certificate from
申请证书来自
Hydra NOC with the SSL Certificate
海德拉NOC附带SSL证书
attached with the existing authentication.
附带现有的认证。
Then the Hydra NOC after receiving
那么Hydra NOC在接收到之后
the certificate request,
证书请求，
will verify this SSL Certificate
将验证此SSL证书
against the local trusted CAs say InCommon,
与本地受信任的CA对照，例如InCommon，
if the Hydra NOC pass it.
如果海德拉NOC通过了。
Then if the validation is successful,
那么如果验证成功，
it will issue
它将颁发
the new certificate to the Hydra app,
它将颁发新证书给Hydra应用程序，
after Hydra app passed
通过Hydra应用程序通过审核后，
the newly issued a certificate,
新颁发的证书，
we will have to trust
我们将不得不信任
anchor initial transfer
锚点初始转移
policies and the certificate.
那么所有的安全政策和证书。
Then all the security
policies and certificates, components are installed here.
components are installed here.
组件在这里安装。
In summary, this work takes
总结来说，这项工作采取了
a first step towards
迈出了第一步
bootstrapping remote NDN entities.
引导远程NDN实体。
Because we found to NDNlize each new entity,
因为我们发现要将每个新实体NDN化，
we should configure the Name,
我们应该配置名称，
Trust Anchor certificate,
信任锚证书，
and Trust Policies into it.
和信任策略整合进去。
Our design makes use of
我们的设计利用了
existing authentication system which
现有的认证系统，它
is the current CAs,
现有的认证机构，
and we were applying
我们正在应用
the same approach to address
解决这一问题的相同方法
remote entity authentication problems
远程实体认证问题
in using arrows like mGUARD,
在使用像mGUARD这样的箭头，
and the NDN AR
和NDN AR
protect as presented yesterday.
保护如昨天所呈现的。
Thanks for listening. That's all
谢谢聆听。就这些了。
my presentation [NOISE].
我的演讲[噪音]。
>> Great. Thank you so much.
>> 非常好。非常感谢你。
This will actually give us a chance
这实际上会给我们一个机会
to catch up on time a little bit.
这实际上会给我们一个机会，让我们稍微赶上一些时间。
I direct all the questions and discussion to
我将所有的问题和讨论都指向
Slack and turn it over
将其放松并翻转过来
to the moderator of the next panel.
向下一个小组的主持人表示感谢。
the speakers in this first session.
这第一场会议的发言人。
>> Thank you Jeff. Marie-Jose you are
>> 谢谢你，Jeff。Marie-Jose，你是
next, go ahead.
接下来，请继续。
[NOISE]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Hey, welcome everyone.
>> 嘿，欢迎大家。
This is the panel number 2.
这是面板号码2。
I'm Marie-Jose Montpetit.
我是玛丽-乔泽·蒙佩蒂。
I'm Affiliate Professor at
我是特聘教授，在
Concordia University in Montreal,
我是特聘教授，在蒙特利尔的康考迪亚大学，很荣幸主持这个小组讨论。
and it is my pleasure to host this panel.
很荣幸主持这个小组讨论。
We had a discussion,
我们进行了讨论，
so Smith, Lofty,
所以史密斯，洛夫蒂，
and I a little bit about this.
我对此略知一二。
We called it NDN beyond NDN and we recognize
我们将其称为超越NDN的NDN，并且我们认识到
the upcoming importance of
即将到来的重要性
data-driven applications
数据驱动的应用程序
and services everywhere.
和到处的服务。
I think the previous session
我认为上一次会议
had the definite,
有明确的，
I would say NDN slant on it.
我会说这是NDN的一种看法。
But data is becoming very
但数据变得越来越重要
important in
数据变得越来越重要，在物联网领域的网络研究尤其如此。
networking research especially in IoT.
网络研究尤其是在物联网领域。
We wanted to put this as a conversation.
我们想把这当作一次对话来进行。
You will see that it is not
你会看到它并非如此
a panel in the sense
一个小组讨论的意义上
people presenting and then
人们接着进行了陈述，然后
waiting then for the questions.
等待着问题的提出。
We would like this to be extremely
我们希望这将非常
interactive between
互动。
the panelists and between
小组成员之间
the panelists and the audience.
小组成员和观众。
A little bit of background.
一点背景。
Again, I just introduced myself.
我刚刚介绍了自己。
The panelists, I think are
我认为小组讨论的嘉宾是
a very good mix of people who are involved
我认为小组讨论的嘉宾是一群参与度很高的优秀人士。
already and have been involved
已经参与并且一直在参与
in NDN research and people who
在NDN研究中和参与其中的人员
were new but come again from
来自于新的但再次出现的
this more and more
越来越多
data-driven research slant in networking.
数据驱动的网络研究倾向。
I don't know if Eve is online.
我不知道伊芙是否在线。
But actually, Eve said that
但实际上，伊芙说过
data was the research fuel
数据是研究的燃料
for the 21st century,
对于21世纪来说，
and I think she was absolutely right.
我认为她绝对正确。
About this time last year
大约在去年的这个时候
with ending full spring
结束了整个春天
of Columbia University,
哥伦比亚大学，
we ran three times two days,
我们连续两天跑了三次，
free workshops on the future of
我们连续两天跑了三次，免费研讨会探讨未来的宽带研究和它
broadband research and it
的宽带研究及其
was broadband research as a whole,
涉及宽带研究的整体情况，包括技术、经济学、社会科学。
technology, economics, social sciences.
技术、经济学、社会科学。
Effectively there were
有效地来说有
very different conclusions.
非常不同的结论。
But one thing that everybody was
但有一件事是每个人都~!@#$%^&*()
sharing was the need to get
分享是获取的需求
more data to learn how to use
更多数据以学习如何使用
the existing data better,
更好地利用现有数据，
to create new ways of capturing data,
创造新的数据捕获方式，
discovering it, sharing it.
发现它，分享它。
It was true that the
它确实是这样的，
data fuels that research in technology,
数据驱动了技术领域的研究，
economy, and social sciences.
经济学和社会科学。
This is what this panel
这就是这个面板~!@#$%^&*()
is a little bit about,
这是关于一点点，
what is data-driven and
数据驱动是什么，以及
how we're going to use it.
我们将如何使用它。
I created a few questions
我创建了一些问题。
and we'll come back to
我们将回到
them after the presentations.
我们将回到他们在报告之后的情况。
Essentially, for the people on
本质上，对于那些在
the panel and also people
在小组讨论中以及观众当中，想一想。
in the audience, think about it.
在观众当中，想一想。
What is the role of data in
数据在你的研究工作中扮演什么角色？
your work on your research,
as a description of your research work?
and would you describe your work
你会如何描述你的工作？
as data-driven?
特别是在物联网领域，作为数据驱动？
Especially in IoT,
特别是在物联网领域，
which is where I work right now,
我目前工作的领域就是这里，
although distributed system,
尽管是分布式系统，
there's this idea
有这样一个观点
of storing, finding, processing.
的存储、查找、处理。
All that data needs
所有那些数据需要
features and operations that
特征和操作可能会有所不同，
are maybe different,
可能会有所不同，
and how are you panelists and people in
与各位嘉宾和在场的朋友们相比，可能会有所不同，the audience addressing this with
the audience addressing this with
观众们正在用这种方式来讨论这个问题。
NDN or non-NDN approaches?
非NDN或NDN方法？
What would be the feature of
What would be the feature of ~!@#$%^&*()
a more data-centric approach to
更加以数据为中心的方法来
distribute systems or IoT,
分布式系统或物联网，
and how could NDN be part of
分布式系统或物联网，NDN如何成为那个解决方案的一部分？我说完了。
that solution? I'm done talking.
那个解决方案？我说完了。
I will ask Dirk,
我会去问Dirk。
who has a hard deadline to present a few of
他必须在截止日期前提交几个
his ideas and then we'll continue with Rute,
他的想法，然后我们会继续和Rute一起，
and then Ike,
和接下来是Ike，
and then Srikathyayani to
接下来是Srikathyayani，
close it from California.
从加利福尼亚关闭它。
I will stop sharing.
我将停止分享。
Dirk you can start sharing.
Dirk，你可以开始分享了。
>> You can hear me now?
>> 你现在能听见我了吗？
[inaudible]. Can you hear me?
[听不清楚]。你能听见我吗？
>> We hear you perfectly.
>> 我们听得很清楚。
>> Okay, good, sorry.
>> 好的，很好，对不起。
I'm going to use a label to the UI.
我将在用户界面上使用一个标签。
Thanks, Marie-Jose.
谢谢，玛丽-约瑟。
Thanks for inviting me here.
谢谢你邀请我来这里。
I just realized this is my fifth organization
我刚意识到这是我加入的第五个组织。
since starting with
自从开始参与以来，
ICN research many years ago.
多年前的ICN研究。
It shows either how old I am or
它显示了我要么是多么的老，要么
how quickly I change organizations.
它显示了我变换组织的速度有多快。
Probably both of it a little bit.
可能两者都有一点。
I went a little bit back,
我回头看了一点，
as you can see from the title,
从标题中你可以看出来，
to the answer that was given in
给出的答案中
the paper bag in 2009 on networking named
2009年关于网络的论文被命名为
content and try to understand
内容并尝试理解
what the question really
问题的真正内容是
was and then trying to address some of
问题的真正内容是，was and then trying to address some of your questions around data.
your questions around data.
围绕数据的问题。
But I was mainly looking at it from what's
但我主要是从什么是的角度来看这个问题。
the importance the data place
数据所占的重要性
when building and looking at some of
构建和审视一些
the approaches that I'm looking at now.
我现在正在考察的方法。
Whoops, sorry,
哎呀，抱歉，
I think I pressed the wrong thing.
我想我按错了东西。
As long as it
只要它
wasn't all about data when we started with,
当我们开始的时候，并不完全是关于数据的，
was NDN already made with data in
当我们开始的时候，并不完全是关于数据的，was NDN already made with data in mind and if you look at data as facts,
mind and if you look at data as facts,
如果你将数据视为事实，
information that are used to calculate,
用于计算的信息，
analyze, and blend something
分析并融合某物
as a definition of Webster.
作为韦伯斯特的一个定义。
They are probably not wrong. Data had
他们可能没有错。数据已经
been as part of
一直是作为一部分
focusing and the very beginning
专注于最初的起点
it was a lot of discussion
有很多讨论
on what particular name
有关于什么特定的名字，
to stick at it,
坚持下去，
and as the paper title suggests
正如论文标题所示
that content was what was used,
该内容正是被使用的内容。
data was also used.
数据也被使用了。
In the very early days,
在非常早期，
we at some point got to information,
我们在某个时候得到了信息，
and the ICN reflects
我们得到了信息，这表明作为以信息为中心的网络(ICN)反映了
that as information-centric networking
我们得到了信息，这表明作为以信息为中心的网络反映了，将信息作为某种不良事物来使用。
to be using information as something bad.
将信息作为某种不良事物来使用。
The thing that I started looking
我开始寻找的事物
into more recently for
近期以来 probably
last 2-3 years probably
近两到三年来可能
is the aspect of computation that
是计算方面的
combines these aspects a little bit together
将这些方面稍微结合在一起
into taking data and making sense out of it.
将数据转化并理解其含义。
Maybe turning it into information,
也许将其转化为信息，
into facts a details about a subject and
将其转化为关于某个主题的事实和细节
allowing me to connect it to a subject.
将其与某个主题联系起来。
Maybe that's the closest to
也许那是最接近于
what content really was meant
这真正意味着什么内容
to mean initially in the paper. I don't know.
这最初在论文中意味着什么，我不知道。
But it's certainly something
但这肯定是某件事情
where in the current research I'm doing
在我目前进行的研究中
permanently move across between data
在我目前进行的研究中, 永久性地在数据之间移动
as data that comes from
作为来自各种来源的数据
various sources IoT being
物联网是来自各种来源的数据之一。
one of the examples.
其中一个例子。
But we're also looking and work for instance
但我们也在寻找并努力工作，例如
in distributed identities
在分布式身份认证中
for EID approaches,
对于电子身份认证方法，
here in Europe at the moment, quite big.
目前在欧洲这边，相当大。
What is it that you could be doing with
~!@#$%^&*()
respect to digital technologies in order
在有序的情况下尊重数字技术
to provide an identity
提供一个身份
framework that would be
提供一个框架，它将会是
highly distributed
高度分布式
maybe rather than being centralized?
或许与其是集中式的，不如是分散式的？
That's another set of
这是另一组
very rich data that's out there that
有很多丰富的数据存在于外面
needs to be combined somehow
需要以某种方式结合起来
through computation to something useful.
通过计算转化为有用的东西。
NDN say if the
~!@#$%^&*()
paradigm change that the networking and
范式的变化在于网络和
content paper was postulating
内容论文是假设
maybe they need move from
也许他们需要从~!@#$%^&*()
the where to the what.
从哪里到什么地方。
Then maybe it all comes way down
那么也许这一切归根到底
to this aspect of the name,
那么也许这一切归根到底，对于这个名字的方面，像什么都可以命名。
like can be named with anything.
像什么都可以命名。
Is it a spectrum
它是一个光谱吗？
between data computation information?
它是一个光谱吗？我们已经看到了各种各样的方法来处理数据计算信息。
We've seen various approaches
我们已经看到了各种各样的方法
when using NDN,
在使用NDN时，
ICN systems for content retrieval,
ICN系统用于内容检索，
static objects for name function.
静态对象用于命名功能。
Networking has extended that to computation,
网络将其扩展到了计算领域，
so naming actually named functions of
so naming actually named functions of computation that could be used,
computation that could be used,
可以使用的计算，
or raw data and IoT.
或原始数据和物联网。
It's the centrality of the name
它是名字的中心性。
that really comes in the end
这最终真的到来了。
down to what is really we want to do
最终归结到我们真正想要做的事情。
in an NDN system or an ICN system.
在一个NDN系统或者一个ICN系统中。
But looking at least the three aspects
但至少从三个方面来看
I put on the left there.
我放在左边了。
The question I think we have been
我认为我们一直在问的问题是
asking throughout the research for
我们在研究过程中一直在问的问题是
many years is data and
多年的数据和~!@#$%^&*()
information retrieval architecture really
信息检索架构确实如此
the best for computation.
确实是计算方面的佼佼者。
That's something I've been
确实是我已经玩弄了很长时间的东西。
Is the flow balance,
流动平衡是...
which is one of the key aspects
它是关键方面之一
in an NDN architecture,
在NDN架构中，
something that is naturally
自然界中的某物
mapped onto computational interactions.
映射到计算交互上。
Can be addressed computation by
可以通过计算来解决
supporting information readability,
支持信息的可读性，
for instance,
例如，
that is reminiscence to some of
这是对一些过去的回忆
the discussions we had many years ago around
我们多年前进行的讨论围绕着
channel semantics that of having
通道语义即拥有个体信息检索语义。
individual information retrieval semantics
个体信息检索语义
as we have the natively.
我们天生就有这种能力。
Another problem in computation that's
计算中的另一个问题是
been keeping me busy
一直让我很忙
is how to support computer affinity?
如何支持电脑亲和性？
What if data follows up with
如果数据接着是
data that just needs to be
只需要被
retrieved from the same entity?
是否需要从同一实体中检索？
Application state, and computation
应用状态和计算
or something that comes to mind
或者是突然想到的事情
where I may end up at a data source,
我可能会在一个数据源结束，
but for the subsequent operations
但对于后续操作
I may need to go back to the data source.
我可能需要回到数据源。
I can't go to another data source
我不能转向另一个数据源。
because the data is intrinsically
因为数据本质上是
linked and therefore will
相互关联，因此将会
need to be pulled from that same source.
需要从同一个来源提取。
The word for that come
The word for that comes from the same source. Up is the affinity part and I know that.
up is the affinity part and I know that
上面是亲和部分，我知道。
someday papers on our computation
有朝一日关于我们计算的论文
ICN I've be talking about
我一直在谈论的ICN
the affinity problem as well.
亲和力问题也是如此。
These are some of the things that
这些是一些
had fired me around and trying to
转来转去试图
see where do these concepts
转来转去试图看看这些概念如何汇聚在一起，以及它们如何
all come together and how can
they be applied within the context of ICN systems in general and the NDN,
ICN systems in general and the NDN,
通常情况下的ICN系统以及NDN，
in particular, support
尤其是支持
the mix of all of those both data,
混合了所有这些数据，
computation, and information,
计算和信息，
and how can we use the architectures
和我们如何能够使用这些架构来妥善支持它们所有
properly to support them all
来妥善支持它们所有
and how can we build not only data systems,
以及我们如何构建不仅仅是数据系统，
but systems have computed
但构建了计算系统
over this data in
~!@#$%^&*()
a distributed manner properly?
分布式方式得当吗？
Hopefully, that gets us to
希望这能帮助我们达到
a couple of discussions.
希望这能帮助我们达到几次讨论。As Marie-Jose said,
As Marie-Jose said,
正如玛丽-乔泽所说，
we want to have a conversation.
我们想要进行一次对话。
I have no particularly good answers.
我没有特别好的答案。
I just wanted to throw out
我只是想说出来
some questions. Thanks.
一些问题。谢谢。
>> Thank you very much. Is Rute
>> 非常感谢。Rute是
in a place where she can
无法立即沟通。
>> Yes finally.
>> 是的，终于。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[BACKGROUND]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Sorry for this I was a bit late.
>> 对不起，我来晚了一点。
Let me share the slides.
让我分享幻灯片。
>> Yes you're next and I realize right now,
是的，你是下一个，我现在意识到了，
that we have three over four
我们有四分之三
panelists from Germany.
来自德国的小组成员。
It's just, I don't
这只是，我不
know down to me, but anyway,
知道对我来说，但无论如何，
it's it's run. Go ahead Rute.
它在运行。继续吧，Rute。
>> Can you see my slides?
>> 你能看到我的幻灯片吗？
>> Yes, but you should go full screen.
是的，但是你应该全屏显示。
Now it's perfect, thank you,.
现在很完美，谢谢你。
>> First of all, hi everybody.
>> 首先，大家好。
I've been working in the NDN on the for
I've been working in the NDN for ~!@#$%^&*()
also maybe a decade and so now I've
也许现在已经有十年左右了我已经
moved through affiliation or
转通过了附属关系或
more prior affiliation and
通过了之前的附属关系和
I've worked mostly with
我主要从事过~!@#$%^&*()
NDN in the context
NDN在此背景下
of opportunistic routing in
机会路由在
wireless environments and currently
无线环境中并且当前
in 40s we are of course,
在40秒内我们当然是，
using NDN more on the device to device
在设备到设备之间更多地使用NDN
communication and more
通信等方面
specifically in decentralized.
特别是在去中心化方面。
Purposely subscribe environments
故意订阅环境
within the manufacturing domain.
在制造领域内。
On my slides I'm going to
在我的幻灯片上我将要
which gives you a little bit
这给了你一点点
more information about this,
这给了你更多关于这个的信息，
so on this slide,
所以在这张幻灯片上，
you see where we are,
您看我们所在的位置，
where we want to apply NDN.
我们希望应用NDN的地方。
Basically from an end-to-end perspective,
从端到端的角度来看，
in terms of manufacturing domains,
在制造领域方面，
we have on the left-hand side
我们在左手边有
different types of devices.
不同类型的设备。
Some devices are, let's say IP enable,
有些设备可以说是支持IP的，
or they have already some semantic capability
或者它们已经具备了一些语义能力。
to be automatically discovered
被自动发现
or connected to an end to end IoT system,
或连接到一个端到端的物联网系统，
but others, brownfield devices normally.
但其他的，旧设备通常会这样。
The robots, etc.
But as for other things, old equipment usually behaves like this. The old robot they...
the old robot they
遗留下的老旧机器人他们
don't and as you possibly know,
不要，而且据你可能知道的，
what is used in these environments are.
在这些环境中使用的是。
Protocols that are specifically
designed for use in these environments, 或者提供一些广泛的安全性，
or that provides some extensive security,
或者提供一些广泛的安全性，
so in the sense that
所以从这个意义上讲，
they create a closed environment,
他们创造了一个封闭的环境，
so that is one aspect of
所以那是其中一个方面。
the second aspect is of course,
第二个方面当然是，
that we have critical applications,
我们拥有关键应用程序，
we need tight control loop
我们需要严密的控制循环。
and these protocols have
和这些协议已经
been developed to support that,
已经被开发出来以支持这一点，
but however one of the issues
但是，然而，其中一个问题是
that is now happening of course,
正在发生的当然是，
is that these environments are
这些环境正在
changing and the communication
正在改变，而且沟通
was normally then in
是通常然后在
a very simple way just to extract some data,
一种非常简单的方式，仅仅用来提取一些数据，
but not the applications that we
但不是我们在工业环境中拥有的应用程序。
have in the industrial environment.
我们在工业环境中拥有的。
They are becoming more data-driven,
他们正变得更加依赖数据驱动，
and they require some more clever way
他们需要一些更聪明的方法
of exchanging data decentralized,
以去中心化的方式交换数据，
but also in a way that
但也以一种方式
can meet the requirements so that
可以满足要求，以便
the timing models that
可以满足要求的时间模型，以便联网部分提供，
the networking part provides,
联网部分提供，
the critical infrastructure setup.
关键基础设施的设置。
One of the things that
我们想要探索的事情之一是在最后因为
of course there we don't have
当然在那里我们没有
the issue with Ip so we wanted to
我们因此想要解决Ip的问题，所以我们想要
explore in the end against
探索最终的对抗
some other approaches such
其他一些方法包括
as OPC way or MQTT.
作为OPC方式或MQTT。
There are different, of course,
当然有所不同，
benefits as we all know,
显而易见的好处，
but there are also as
但也存在着
explained a few challenges.
解释了一些挑战。
The first one, which is possibly
第一个，可能是
not critical at the current stage in
当前阶段不是关键的在
manufacturing domains relates with
制造领域相关联的
mobility and in particular
流动性，尤其是
the producer mobility.
生产者的流动性。
Even though it's not critical,
即使这不是关键的，
the fact is that it has to be
事实上，这必须得到解决，而且还有
addressed and there are
必须得到解决，而且还有
environments where of course,
必须得到解决，而且还有环境在哪里当然，我们有移动机器人和
we have mobile robots and
我们有移动机器人和
also mobile devices such as AGVs.
我们还有自动引导车等移动设备。
It would be helpful to have
有这个会很有帮助
a decentralized
去中心化的
communication approach that would
通信方式将会
allow these devices to exchange
允许这些设备交换
data directly among themselves.
数据直接在它们之间交换。
But of course, again, this is not
但当然，再次强调，这并不是
a critical aspect and there are
一个关键方面，还有
a few mechanisms that have been
几种已经被发展出来的机制
developed based on anchor points, etc.
基于锚点等已经开发出的机制。
There are other things that we can do.
我们还可以做其他事情。
Integrate mobility suppressor mechanisms
整合移动性抑制机制
of machine learning to
整合机器学习以
improve the mobility, etc.
改善机动性等。
I would say that this is not
我会说这不是
really a key challenge,
我会说这不是真的一个关键挑战，but however, it's something
but however, it's something
但无论如何，这还是个问题。
that in the future will have to be handled.
在未来将不得不处理的问题。
Other telling that are more
其他更为重要的叙述。
relevant in the context
相关的语境中
of this industrial demands
的这些工业需求
relate to the naming part so NDN
与命名部分相关，所以NDN
has of course a very expressive
拥有非常丰富的表现力
and quite flexible naming space.
拥有相当灵活的命名空间。
But the way we are currently handling it
但我们目前处理它的方式
means that when applying
意味着在应用时
it to the industrial domain,
将其应用于工业领域，
we would be creating, again,
我们将再次创造，
the same problem that we have where
我们所面临的同一个问题在于
the semantic descriptions of
我们所面临的同一个问题在于，语义描述的~!@#$%^&*() machines not just have sensors,
machines not just have sensors,
机器不仅仅是有传感器，
are basically tie it to
基本上是将其绑定到
a protocol or to invocation architecture.
一个协议或调用架构。
There we can do different things.
在那里我们可以做不同的事情。
We can work on translation.
我们可以进行翻译工作。
I would say that would be the first stage.
我会说那将是第一阶段。
But of course, we need also to look ahead.
但当然，我们也需要向前看。
Then for these environments, of course,
那么对于这些环境来说，当然，
there's also the issue with
这些环境还存在一个问题，当然，the pool variance model that NDNs of course,
the pool variance model that NDNs of course,
这些环境还存在一个问题，当然，NDNs的池变异模型，
we also have the possibility
我们也有可能
of support was push-based communication,
的支持是基于推送的沟通方式，
but they will have to be adjusted to
但它们将不得不进行调整以适应
serve the IoT requirements again,
服务于物联网的需求再次，
where we have very
在这里我们有非常严格和苛刻的要求
critical and strict requirements
严格和关键的要求
like bounded latency below one millisecond.
像延迟时间低于一毫秒的严格限制。
More interesting,
更有趣的是，
at least was in terms of what we
至少在我们所做的方面来说，是什么能力
are doing is the capability
to do centralized synchronization.
to do centralized synchronization.
进行集中式同步。
Multi-party data
多方数据同步。
We have a few options available such as
我们有几种可用的选项，例如
vector sync or coronal sync
矢量同步或冠状同步
and this is definitely interesting.
这确实很有趣。
Just to explain a little bit
只是稍微解释一下
what we are trying to do right now.
我们现在正在尝试做的事情。
In, a live environment,
在一个实时的环境中，
we are currently basically starting again,
我们目前基本上是重新开始，
so trying to prepare
我们目前基本上是重新开始，所以尝试着做准备，and to propose adaptations.
and to propose adaptations.
并提出适应性调整。
When the end, so what
当一切结束时，那又如何？
you have on the left-hand side is
你在左手边有的是
basically an example of where we want to go.
基本上是我们想去的地方的一个例子。
So where we have the AGV is
所以我们有自动引导车(AGV)的地方是
directly communicating among themselves.
直接相互通信。
But also to the pickups stations,
但也对接货站，
let's say to the task servers and
我们可以说是对任务服务器而言，
on the right-hand side is what we are
我们正在做的就是位于右手边。
doing currently to test this.
我们目前正在做的就是测试这个。
What we want to understand is not
我们想要了解的不是
just a course to look comparison
我们想要了解的不是just a course to look comparison against MQTT or a broker approach.
against MQTT or a broker approach.
对比MQTT或经纪人方法。
We want to go a little bit beyond that.
我们想要做得更进一步。
We actually would like to compare it to
我们实际上想要将它与~!@#$%^&*()比较
the **** so the approach of OPC way,
我们实际上想要将它与~!@#$%^&*()比较, the **** so the approach of OPC way, which is based on multicast and
which is based on multicast and
它基于多播和
also so try to convince,
也尽力去说服，
let's say, the industrial
让我们说，工业
IoT people that NDN
物联网领域中的NDN人员
is definitely so the vendors for instance,
绝对是这样，例如供应商们，
NDN is definitely an approach that should be
NDN绝对是应该被考虑支持这种去中心化的方法
considered to support this decentralization
应该被考虑支持这种去中心化
on the shop floors.
在车间地板上。
This is my last slide. Thank you.
这是我的最后一张幻灯片。谢谢。
>> Thank you so much.
>> 非常感谢。
Thank you for accommodating
非常感谢您的体谅。
this while you were traveling.
在您旅行的时候，您提出了这个问题。
I think you're raising a number of
我认为你提出了许多
important questions that we're going to
重要的问题，我们将要
come back to in, I think,
重要的问题，我们将要回到我认为，在NDN和数据中心研究方面
NDN and data centric research in
NDN和面向数据中心的研究在
general is this raise of the edge,
总的来说，这是边缘的崛起，
the edge networks, the edge computing,
边缘网络、边缘计算，
and essentially the IIoT and where
在本质上是工业物联网(IIoT)以及它所在的领域
there is probably a lot of
可能有很多
opportunities and we already saw this.
可能有很多机会，我们已经看到了这一点。
This is actually the perfect segue into,
这实际上是一个完美的过渡，进入下一个话题，
I know Ike is going to talk about.
我知道Ike将要讨论的内容。
Ike, please present.
Ike，请开始报告。
[NOISE].
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Yeah, hello everyone.
>> 嗨，大家好。
Let me also quickly
让我也快速地
see which screen to share right now.
看看现在应该分享哪个屏幕。
That's the wrong one, I guess.
那应该是错的，我猜。
Then let's try the other one.
那我们试试另一个吧。
Now you should see the correct screen.
现在你应该看到正确的屏幕了。
Hello everyone.
大家好。
Thank you very much for the introduction
非常感谢你的介绍
and the invitation, Marie-Jose.
和邀请，Marie-Jose。
I guess I'm one of the people
我想我是其中一个人
who are not that directly involved in
没有直接参与其中的
NDN because from my background I'm
没有直接参与其中的，因为根据我的背景，我是
rather working on computing
没有直接参与其中的，因为根据我的背景，我是rather working on computing and the network only right now.
and the network only right now.
并且目前仅专注于计算和网络。
I'm Ike Kunze, I'm a PhD student at
我是Ike Kunze，我是德国RWTH亚琛工业大学的博士研究生。
RWTH Aachen University in Germany.
德国亚琛工业大学。
What I would like to do today is
我今天想做的是
give an outside view into the topics.
提供一个关于这些话题的外部视角。
I'm generally familiar with NDN and such.
我对NDN之类的东西相当熟悉。
But yeah, I'm not
但是，我不是
actively working on the topic and what
积极地研究这个话题以及什么
I would like to do here is basically give you
我想在这里做的基本上是给你
my current work, what I'm doing.
我目前的工作，我正在做的事情。
I'm working in a German research project
我正在参与一个德国研究项目。
that is focusing on bringing
该项目专注于引进
Internet technology to
互联网技术以
industrial networks but quite similar to
工业网络，但与此相当类似
what we've seen on the previous talk by Rute.
我们在Rute之前的演讲中所见到的内容。
Actually, I thought one slide is really
实际上，我认为有一张幻灯片确实是
similar to what I'm about to show you.
实际上，我认为有一张幻灯片确实是类似于我马上要展示给你们看的。
What we have in our project are a lot
我们的项目中有很多
of different demonstrators
的不同示范者
and machines that we have.
和我们拥有的机器。
What I've put here on the slide
我在幻灯片上放了什么
is fine blanking line, for example.
基本上是一条精细冲压线，例如。
Basically, a high
基本上是一条高
precision stamping process where we
精密冲压工艺，我们可以
stamp metal or a high pressure
冲压金属或是高压
die casting process where we basically have
压铸工艺，我们基本上是在进行
molten metal that we push into
熔融金属，我们将其推入
a form which we then
一种形式，然后我们
used to create large pots,
用来制作大型罐子，
for example, for the car manufacturing.
例如，用于汽车制造。
One of the first goals of
我们研究项目的首要目标之一是
our research project is
我们的研究项目是
basically to interconnect all
基本上是为了将所有这些不同的机器互联。
of these different machines,
这些不同的机器，
also from different locations,
也来自不同的地点，
and just to try and
也只是为了尝试和
then create and gather
然后创建和收集
as much data as possible.
尽可能收集更多的数据。
I think that was brought
我认为那是被带来的
quite good to the point by
相当不错，直截了当。
Rute and Marie-Jose before.
鲁特和玛丽-何塞以前。
We're just trying to gather
我们只是在尽可能地收集
as much data as possible.
我们只是在尽可能地收集尽可能多的数据。
Then on the right hand side you can see
然后在右手边你可以看到
a couple of passwords.
一些密码。
Basically, we want to then try to derive
基本上，我们接下来想要尝试推导出
as much information out of that data
尽可能多地从那些数据中提取信息
as possible to then finally,
尽可能地然后最终，
improve the processes themselves.
改进这些过程本身。
However, in typical industrial settings,
然而，在典型的工业环境中，
what we see is
我们所看到的是
that the communication patterns
我们所看到的是，交流模式are rather static.
are rather static.
我们所看到的是，交流模式相当固定。
For example, you would only set
例如，您只需设置
up the connection to the Cloud 1s
连接到云端1秒
or if you have a fixed supply chain,
或者如果你有一个固定的供应链，
for example, you will only set
例如，你将只会设置
up the communication channels
设置通信渠道
between those different parties.
在这些不同的各方之间。
What I personally I'm looking at
我个人正在关注的是
is how we can make everything
是如何让一切变得
a bit more flexible by also deploying
一点更灵活地部署
compute functionality and
计算功能以及
additional functionality in the network.
网络中的附加功能。
For example, if we have a lot of
例如，如果我们有很多
analysis tasks in the Cloud then how can we,
分析任务在云端，那么我们应该如何操作，
for example, move some
例如，移动一些
of that functionality into the network
将该功能移动到网络中
so that we can improve
以便我们可以提高
the overall performance.
整体表现。
But also, on the other hand,
但另一方面，
I'm interested in finding out how we can
我有兴趣了解我们如何能够
actually make direct use of the data.
实际上直接利用这些数据。
We look at the data and try to find
我们查看这些数据并尝试找出这些数据最适合放置的位置。
out where these data is best suited to go.
我们尝试找出这些数据最适合放置的位置。
To illustrate that a bit
为了进一步阐释这一点
let us quickly make this a bit
让我们迅速使这个变得有点
more easy and then also
让我们迅速使这个变得有点更容易，然后也看看这个位于底部的情节。
look at this plot at the bottom.
看看这个位于底部的情节。
What you can see here is basically
你在这里看到的基本上是
a liifetime of the pipe linking process.
一生中的管道连接过程。
We have a very characteristic
我们有一个非常有特色的
signal, the punch force.
我们有一个非常有特色的信号，基本上是拳头的力量。
Basically the force with
我们有一个非常有特色的信号，基本上是拳头的力量，通过金属被打出的方式。
which the metal is punched.
它是金属被打出的信号。
As we can see, the signal at the beginning is
我们可以看到，最开始的信号是
rather fluctuating then it
变得相对稳定了。
gets a bit more stable.
变得稍微稳定一些。
Then afterwards it starts to fluctuate even
然后之后它开始波动得更加剧烈。
more in these different phases.
我们可以将这个过程分为不同的阶段。
along those different phases.
沿着这些不同的阶段。
What we are now trying to
我们现在尝试的是沿着这些不同的阶段，基本上做的就是检测
do is basically detect
我们基本上做的就是检测
these different stages or phases of
这些不同的阶段或者说是发展的阶段
the process already on networking devices.
这个过程已经在网络设备上运行。
For example, that if we are in
例如，如果我们在
a product controlled setting,
在一个产品受控环境中，
then we don't need all the information,
那么我们就不需要所有的信息，
but we might only be
但我们可能只会对记录这些信息感兴趣，
interested in logging the information and
我们可能只对记录这些信息感兴趣，并且
sending them to the Cloud
将它们发送到云端
for example, a deeper inspection.
例如，更深入的检查。
Or if we are in
或者如果我们在
a face where the process seems to go wild,
一张脸上的过程似乎变得狂野，
that we can just
我们可以仅仅
identify that and then send all the data to
识别出那个然后发送所有数据到
a process near a edge
边缘附近的一个过程
Cloud where we then have
我们随后所在的云端
the clause that control
控制的那个条款
that Rute was talking about earlier as well.
鲁特之前也提到过的那个。
In this way, what we're trying to
我们尝试的是这样的，
do is really try to make use of the data,
我们真的是尽力利用这些数据，
to also find out
来还发现
where we want to send the data.
我们想要发送数据的地方。
As I said, I'm looking from
正如我所说，我在从外部向内在NDN上寻找我们想要发送数据的地方。
the outside in on NDN
在NDN上从外部向内部
and that's what I would, for example,
而那正是我会，例如，
be interested is finding
感兴趣的是去发现
out whether these concepts are actually
是否这些概念实际上是
supportable by NDN or whether they map to
支持NDN还是它们映射到
NDN and if so how this is actually done.
支持NDN吗？如果支持，这实际上是如何做到的。
Because I'm just interested
因为我只是感兴趣
in how this would then work.
在这将如何运作。
Yeah, with that, I'm through to my slides.
是的，有了那个，我就可以进入我的幻灯片环节了。
Thank you very much and I'm
非常感谢，我是
looking forward to the discussion.
期待这次讨论。
>> Thank you. I guess all participants,
>> 谢谢。我猜所有的参与者，
I don't see a lot of questions yet,
我还没有看到很多问题，
but you can see that we're starting to have
但你可以看到我们开始有了
this trend of compute things aggregate,
这种计算事物聚合的趋势，
things need to be discovered.
物事需要被发现。
I think this is something that is common to
我认为这是一些共通之处。
both the data centric and the NDN world.
在数据中心和NDN世界都是如此。
We'll end, and it's not the least,
我们将结束，但这并不是最不重要的，
it's the last person but somebody
它是最后一个人，但还有其他人。
who brings another view from industry
他从行业中带来了另一种观点。
This is Srikathyayani from Intel,
我是来自英特尔的Srikathyayani。
who actually is participating
谁实际上是参与者？
in this in spite of having an accident.
非常感谢您即使出了事故也参与了这个。
Thank you so much for doing this in
Thank you so much for doing this despite your accident.
spite of your accident.
尽管你出了事故。
I'm very happy that you can do it.
我很高兴你能做到。
I will let you talk about your work in MDM
我会让你谈论你在MDM中的工作。
because you are really
因为你真的
involved in the community.
参与社区活动。
>> Thank you so much, Marie-Jose.
>> 非常感谢你，Marie-Jose。
Yes, I had
是的，我有过
an unfortunate accident a couple of
几天前的一个不幸事故，我道歉
days ago and I apologize
几天前我道歉
for not having slides.
因为没有准备幻灯片。
My vision is still blurry and
我的视线仍然模糊不清，
I need to be in a darkroom,
我需要待在一个暗室里，
so thank you for bearing with me.
所以感谢你一直忍受我。
I'm Srikathyayani Srikanteswara.
我是Srikathyayani Srikanteswara。
I am a Principal Engineer at
我是一名主要工程师，在
Intel Labs and I currently am leading
Intel实验室，我目前担任领导职务
research and using Endian for
研究并使用Endian进行
dynamic orchestration at the Edge
在边缘进行动态编排
and also how to adapt and
以及如何适应和
transition these technologies into industry.
将这些技术转移到工业应用中。
Now, my remarks will be very much
现在，我的话将会非常
aligned to what has been mentioned already.
符合前面已经提到的内容。
Data is everywhere and
数据无处不在，
it's gaining importance,
它越来越重要，
but the key is, data
但关键是，数据
needs to be analyzed, interpreted.
需要被分析、解释。
When that happens, that creates more data.
当那种情况发生时，就会产生更多的数据。
What that means is,
这意味着，
data and compute usually go together.
数据和计算通常是相辅相成的。
The other point I want to mention is
我想提及的另一个要点是
But data is everywhere and so is compute.
但是数据无处不在，计算能力也同样无处不在。
But a lot of it is not getting used today.
但是今天很多数据并没有被利用起来。
What am I talking about? We all
我在说什么呢？我们都
know about Edge Computing.
在线边缘计算方面我们都有所了解。
As we're bringing servers
我们正在将服务器带得更靠近边缘，
maybe at the 5G base station and so on.
也许是在5G基站等地方。
But there are further a lot
但还有更多的
more compute resources that are
但还有更多的计算资源
available that do not participate
可用的但并未参与其中
in this providing data or Edge Computing.
在提供数据或边缘计算方面。
I'm talking about the processing
我在谈论处理，在提供数据或边缘计算方面，of CPU in cars,
of CPU in cars,
的汽车中的CPU，
maybe a server in the Starbucks,
或许是星巴克里的一台服务器，
your PC in a home,
你家里的个人电脑上，
or even on a PC in
你家里的个人电脑上，或者在一台位于
a factory floor that is not
一间还没有完工的工厂车间
part of your factory Cloud
部分工厂云
and doesn't participate in Edge Computing.
并且不参与边缘计算。
What I want to mention is,
我想要提及的是，
Endian actually has this unique ability
Endian实际上具有这种独特的能力
to bring all of these devices,
将所有这些设备带来，
compute data resources that don't
计算不使用的数据资源
participate in
参与
this Edge Computing data transport,
这种边缘计算数据传输，
all of that into the fold.
将所有这些纳入考量。
I think that is one place where we
我认为那是一个我们可以真正展现出独特特色的地方。
can truly bring out the unique features
可以真正展现出独特特色
or benefits of Endian
或者Endian的好处
in an industry that might be
在一个可能会……的行业
otherwise reluctant to change
否则不愿意改变
from IP or the way they do things.
从IP或者他们处理事情的方式。
The unique features of Endian,
从Endian的独特特征，
I don't need to explain
我不需要解释
the benefits of an Endian.
Endian的好处。
But the features of Endian that would
Endian的特性将会
help here in the scenario that
在这种情况下
I mentioned is the fact
我提到的是事实
that Endian can bridge
Endian可以桥接
wireless networks a lot
无线网络很多
more easily than say IP.
比如说IP，更容易。
Because at the network layer,
因为在网络层，
you don't really care whether I'm sending out
你并不真的在乎我是否在发送
my interest packet or
~!@#$%^&*()
a Wi-Fi network or a Bluetooth,
无线网络或蓝牙，
5G, or anything else.
5G或其他任何东西。
There is that big advantage
有那么大的优势
and I think that needs to be
我认为那需要被
exploited and brought out even better.
被开发利用并且进一步提升。
Also Endian has this unique ability
Endian还拥有这种独特的能力
of bridging data silos.
打破数据孤岛。
Especially news cases like smart city,
尤其是像智能城市这样的新闻案例，
which is I guess related
它我猜是有关联的
to parts some would call it
它有些部分被称作它
part of IoT use case.
物联网用例的一部分。
You have data in
您有数据在
silos transportation system,
粮仓运输系统，
may be weather system,
可能是气候系统，
in cars, in
汽车里，在
the electricity department and so on.
电力部门等等。
All of these need to come together.
所有这些都需要结合起来。
Especially if you have
特别是如果你有
a common naming scheme and metadata
一个通用的命名方案和元数据
and visibility to that
以及对此的可见性
and along with trust schemes,
以及信任机制，
Endian offers that unique ability
Endian提供了独特的能力
for these use cases.
对于这些用例来说。
The other point I want to bring
我想提出的另一个观点是
out is especially
出色的是
in some of the use cases
在某些用例中
like IoT or in the factory floor,
像物联网或工厂车间，
where data is created at
在数据产生的地方
the Edge and used at the Edge,
在边缘处产生并在边缘处使用，
traditional CDN-like approaches will
传统的CDN方式将
not work because a lot of times
不起作用，因为很多时候
that's the argument that I get is,
这就是我得到的论点是，
"I need to transfer data
between different systems, and from what I've gathered,"
, Endian does so much better.
，Endian的表现要好得多。
We'll just use a CDN."
我们将会使用一个CDN。
CDNs work great when data is at
CDN在数据位于的时候表现非常好。
the core and flows to the Edge.
核心和流向边缘。
But in areas like
但在像这样的领域
IoT where data is
物联网，在这样的领域中，数据是在边缘生成和使用的，
generated and used at the Edge,
在边缘生成和使用，
that architecture doesn't work very well.
这种架构效果不是很好。
Along these lines, we actually
沿着这些思路，我们实际上在内部开发了一种算法。
developed an algorithm within
我们在内部开发了一种算法
Endian for dynamic orchestration where we
端对端的动态编排，我们在这里
bring together data,
汇总数据，
compute, there is
计算，有
the hardware resource and
硬件资源和~!@#$%^&*()
software together in real time.
软件能够实时协同工作。
That is, they get
即是说，他们获得
discovered in real-time and they come
发现是实时的，他们来到
together in real-time and we
一起实时地，我们
publish these in Globcom.
在Globcom上发布这些。
What we found is, in addition to,
我们发现的是，除了，
we can indeed discover these in
我们确实可以在这些中发现
real-time and bring
实时并且将
them together in real-time.
将它们实时地结合在一起。
What we were able to show is,
我们能够展示的是，
even if these servers,
即使是这些服务器，
let's say they're on for five seconds,
假设它们开启五秒钟，
they go away, they disappear.
它们消失了，它们不见了。
We're able to continuously
我们能够持续地发现新资源并利用它们。
discover new resources and use them.
发现新资源并使用它们。
It supports dynamism, which is
它支持动态性，这是Endian非常独特的特点。
a very unique feature of Endian.
Endian的一个非常独特的特性。
Another thing we found
我们还发现了另一件事情
that we weren't even looking for it
我们甚至没有刻意去寻找它
is load balancing becomes quite automatic.
负载均衡变得相当自动化了。
There is so much effort that's being put
如今已经投入了大量的努力。
today in how to do
今天怎么做
a load balancing and what am I referring to?
负载均衡，我指的是什么？
Is, let's say I have two head servers,
假设我有两个主服务器，
suddenly a third head server
突然出现了第三个头服务器
comes on, a fourth.
出现了第四个。
Automatically the interest packets
自动发送兴趣数据包
start going to the servers
开始前往服务器
that are less occupied because they say,
他们说，因为那些不太繁忙。
"Hey, I'm free," they respond.
"嘿，我有空，"他们回应。
We see that the load is being
我们看到负载正在被
shared equally among the different servers.
负载正在平均分配到不同的服务器上。
These results, as I said they're in local,
这些结果，正如我所说的，它们是本地的，
unfortunately, I'm not able
遗憾的是，我无法做到
to show them to you right now.
向你展示它们。
But then we took
但后来我们拿出来
all these results and then we went
所有这些结果，然后我们去了
and spoke to some people
和一些人交谈了
who are building these end-to-end systems,
正在构建这些端到端系统的人员，
working in these areas.
在这些领域工作。
Some of the interesting insights
一些有趣的见解
I want to share with you are,
我想和你分享的是，
a lot of these areas,
很多这些地区，
as you're already aware,
由于您已经知道，
people are used to working with IP,
人们习惯了使用IP工作，
with the system they have.
他们拥有的系统。
There is so much of history there.
那里有着丰富的历史。
There's so much of
~!@#$%^&*()
code already existing there.
代码已经存在那里。
When they see a lot of these results,
当他们看到很多这样的结果时，
they understand it, they're excited.
他们明白了，他们很兴奋。
But the other thing that we heard was,
但我们听到的另一件事是，
if you want us to
如果你想让我们
change the way we are doing things,
改变我们的做事方式，
when there is a solution,
改变我们的做事方式，当有一个解决方案时，我们想要看到2倍的效果，
we want to see 2x,
我们想要看到2倍的效果，
3x maybe 10x gains and
我们想要看到3倍甚至10倍的效果增益，然后我们才会考虑改变。
performance before we are going to change.
我们才会考虑改变之前，我们希望看到至少50%的效果提升。
If we see even if a 50 percent improvement
在我们看到至少50%的效果提升之前，
the effort and changing the code,
努力修改代码，
no I'm not interested,
不，我不感兴趣。
which personally to me
对我个人来说
as a researcher was a little surprising,
作为一名研究者，这有点让人惊讶，
but it gets coming from
但它不断地来自于
people who are implementing these everyday.
正在将这些日常实践付诸实施的人们。
It makes sense.
这是有道理的。
The other point I want to make is,
我想要表达的另一个观点是，
a lot of these changes in
许多这些变化已经在
industry are already happening in
行业中已经在发生。
terms of you going towards naming or
您朝着命名方向发展时的条款或
like when you take service meshes or
像当您采用服务网格或者
even OPC UA has a pub-sub feature.
即使OPC UA也具有发布-订阅功能。
Some of these aspects
这些方面中的一些
are already beginning to
已经开始慢慢渗透到行业中去。
But what I want to urge
但我想要强调的是
the Endian Community is,
Endian社区是，
it would really help if we integrate,
它将会非常有帮助，如果我们整合，
if all of us and this
如果我们所有人和这个
is a request one at all.
如果我们所有人和这个请求是一个整体。
If we take an integrate Endian
如果我们采取一个整体的Endian方法，
into existing popular applications.
集成到现有的流行应用程序中。
I heard Kubernetes mentioned a few times,
我听说了几次Kubernetes，
those are some of the software
这些是一些软件
that's being used ubiquitously.
这些正在被普遍使用。
If we can show easily, just use this step,
如果我们能轻松展示，只需使用这个步骤，
this piece of code,
这段代码，
and you can have
这段代码，你可以拥有
part of your application in IP,
应用程序的一部分在IP中，
part of it in Endian and you get
一部分在Endian中，你会得到
all these benefits when you
在Endian中，你会得到所有这些好处当你
use them in Endian,
使用它们在Endian中，
I think that would go a long way in
我认为那将会大有帮助。
industries realizing the benefits
行业意识到了这些好处
of Endian and actually adopting them.
行业意识到了这些好处，并且实际上开始采用它们。
Then of course finally, last but not least,
那么当然，最后但同样重要的是，
when you start looking at data
当你开始查看数据
along with compute,
伴随着计算，
there are some new security challenges
伴随着计算，出现了一些新的安全挑战。
that come up as in,
随之出现的是，比如说，
how do you know you are
你怎么知道你是~!@#$%^&*()
authorized to access compute,
授权访问计算资源，
the access control, trusted computing,
访问控制，可信计算，
verifiable computing and so on.
可验证计算等。
We're actually
我们实际上
collaborating with the professors,
与教授们合作，
Jamie Shen, Riza [inaudible] on this.
Jamie Shen，Riza [无法听清] 这方面。
But I think that these were some
但我认为这些是一些
of the things I wanted to mentioned
我想提及的事情之一
and l will conclude with that.
并且我将以此作为结束。
>> Thank you so much.
>> 非常感谢您。
It was such a good summary
这是一个非常好的总结
in the way of everything
在一切事物的方式中
we need to talk about.
我们需要谈谈。
I think Rute you
我认为你，Rute ~!@#$%^&*()
are the one who seems to be getting a lot
是似乎得到很多问题的那个人来自Slack。
of questions from the Slack.
来自Slack的问题支持。
There were things about the support
来自支持的事情
for mobility.
为了移动性。
Would you like to share with us a little bit
您愿意和我们分享一些吗？
what are the topics
您愿意和我们分享一些吗？您在Slack上讨论的主题是什么？
you've been discussing on the Slack?
您在Slack上讨论了什么？
>> Yes. Sorry, I was just unmuting.
是的。抱歉，我刚才在解除静音。
In terms of producing mobility,
在生产移动性方面，
there are a few questions
有几个问题
about the solutions that
关于解决方案，我们今天有几个问题，当然，
we have today and of course,
我们今天有，当然，
we have some solution.
我们有一些解决方案。
I said, I don't think that
我说，我不认为那
mobility is a critical part,
流动性是一个关键部分，
at least to convince somebody
至少要说服某人
manufacturing that Endian could be
制造那可能是Endian的~!@#$%^&*()
interesting because we have other problems.
有趣的是，我们还有其他问题。
But however, here the idea
但是，然而，这里的想法
is that we have
我们所拥有的是
environments where the producer,
生产者所在的环境，
so we are using Endian on top of Ethernet.
所以我们在以太网之上使用Endian。
Of course, the providers
当然，提供商
are robots that are eventually
最终成为的机器人
sending information with a short interval.
以短时间间隔发送信息。
Small messages of course
当然是小信息。
normally but critical messages.
通常是关键信息。
The other aspect that I think
我认为的另一个方面是
is more interesting was,
我认为的另一个方面是更有趣的是，let me just see,
let me just see,
我看看，
I'm trying to browse related
我在尝试浏览相关
with the comment I think
我认为这个评论说的是
by Dirk that of course we have
我认为这个评论说的是，当然我们有 the capability to push.
the capability to push
我们有推进的能力
the semantics part and
语义部分和
whether this is sufficient.
这是否足够。
I would say this is
我会说这是
definitely a starting point,
绝对是一个起点，
the question, this is
这绝对是一个起点，问题是，至少
a question because at least
这绝对是一个问题，因为至少
I didn't write operationally.
我没有按照操作流程来写。
We have to send also some parameter,
我们还需要发送一些参数，
not just from the producers,
不仅来自生产者，
but also sensor parameters,
但也包括传感器参数，
for instance,
例如，
time synchronization parameters,
时间同步参数，
etc, that are important.
等等，这些都很重要。
The question is whether we can do it or not
这个问题是我们能否做到。
with this synchronization approaches.
与这些同步方法相结合。
This would be the synchronization approaches.
这将是同步方法。
[NOISE]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> This actually this
这实际上是这样
follows of course some of questions by
随之而来的当然还有一些问题
Ike in terms of how can
Ike 在如何方面可以帮助他在工厂车间。
Endian help him on the factory floor.
Endian 可以在工厂车间帮助他。
I think from what we heard also,
我认为根据我们所听到的，
I was pleased with Tatiana.
我对塔蒂亚娜感到满意。
mentioning
提到
the different data sources
不同的数据来源
and the fact that all of
和所有这些事实
these systems were lines and in terms of IoT,
这些系统是线性的，并且就物联网而言，
we need to use them horizontally
我们需要横向使用它们。
and I'm facing this problem all the time.
我一直面临着这个问题。
I think this is also [NOISE]
我认为这也是[噪音]
an interesting question going back to Dirk.
一个有趣的问题又回到了Dirk那里。
Well, Dirk, I'm throwing you the ball
嗯，Dirk，我把球扔给你了。
now because you
现在因为你
raise this idea if the data was the answer.
如果数据是答案，那么提出这个想法。
What is the problem? I think,
如果数据是答案，那么我认为，
first there's the power of rebel of
首先是反叛的力量。
all those data systems and how do you
所有这些数据系统以及你如何
feel that an NDN and ICN can help there.
管理这些数据系统以及你如何感觉一个NDN和一个ICN在这里可以提供帮助。
I will tell you that for
我会告诉你为什么~!@#$%^&*()
the same reason that Srikathyayani.
相同的原因，那就是Srikathyayani。
I call you Srikathyayani
我叫你Srikathyayani。
because I know somebody
因为我认识某个人
that's called that way.
这就是所谓的那样。
I'm sorry, I'm missing your name.
很抱歉，我不知道您的名字。
>> Just like me just an E and
>> 就像我，只是一个E和
N. By the way I had
N. 顺便说一下我有~!@#$%^&*()
a comment about an ability
关于一项能力的评论
if it's okay to share that one.
如果可以分享那个的话。
>> Before your talk, I think
在你的演讲之前，我认为
you were right in
在你的演讲之前，我认为你是对的在提到需要有
mentioning the need to have
提到需要具备
much better performance so that people
的性能要好得多，以便人们
will do their transition.
会进行他们的过渡。
Go ahead maybe you can answer
请继续，或许你可以回答。
that [inaudible] ability and then Dirk,
那个[听不清]能力，然后Dirk，
I really want to have your idea
我真的很想知道你的想法。
about what do we do with the Tower of Babel?
我们该怎么处理巴别塔呢？
[BACKGROUND]
~!@#$%^&*()
[OVERLAPPING]
[重叠]
>> Sorry.
对不起。
Did you want me to go ahead or did
你是想让我先走，还是说……
you want Dirk to go ahead first?
你是想让迪尔克先走吗？
>> No, go ahead.
>> 不，你先走吧。
>> Srikathyayani.
>> ~!@#$%^&*()
>> Okay, I just want you to add to
>> 好的，我只是想让你添加到
Rute's comment on mobility, some good news.
鲁特关于流动性的评论，一些好消息。
You're not quite in the
你还没有完全进入状态
TSM factory floor contexts.
TSM工厂车间背景。
But we actually were able
但我们实际上能够
to simulate in ndnSIM.
模拟在ndnSIM中。
This is not an actual implementation,
这不是一个实际的实现，
but in simulation where we have a bunch of
但在模拟中，我们有一堆
cars moving along the road
在道路上行驶的汽车
and then there are some access points.
然后还有一些接入点。
But at this over by five
但是在这边超过了五个
because it's a lot easier in ndnSIM.
因为在ndnSIM中这会容易得多。
Then, of course, we had resources data on
然后，当然，我们有资源数据在
the cars as well as in the fixed part and NDN
汽车以及在固定部分和NDN上也是如此。
was able to work just fine and
能够顺利工作，以及
that was the dynamism where I
那是我所体验到的活力所在。
said where you have the car resource just for
刚才你说你有车资源只是为了
a few seconds and then it's
几秒钟之后就
gone and it works.
几秒钟之后就消失了，它起作用了。
Not quite the factory floor situation,
并不完全是工厂车间的情况，
the TSM, the type controls,
the TSM, the type controls, ~!@#$%^&*()
but in other forms of mobility it does work.
但在其他形式的移动性中它是有效的。
>> Okay. Dirk, again,
好的。Dirk，再来一次。
I would like you to have this.
我想让你拥有这个。
What are your views on
What are your views on ~!@#$%^&*()
all this data orchestration that is needed?
所有这些所需的数据编排？
All the fact that they use
他们使用的所有事实
different semantic models.
不同的语义模型。
Again, you're the one who
再次，你是那个人
started if data's the answer,
如果数据是答案的开始，
what's the problem and I think the lack of
那么问题是什么，我认为缺乏
common interfaces actually Captain Yana,
公共接口实际上是指的，Yana船长，
you mentioned orchestration as being
你提到编排是
a big problem so I will
一个很大的问题，所以我将会
throw back the question to you, Dirk.
把问题抛回给你，Dirk。
We know some of the problems.
我们知道一些问题。
What do you think are the answers?
你认为答案是什么？
>> Well, I don't have a very good answer.
嗯，我没有一个很好的答案。
I'm usually just asking questions.
我通常只是在问问题。
>> That's why I'm asking you a question
>> 这就是为什么我要问你一个问题。
[OVERLAPPING]
~!@#$%^&*()
[inaudible] at answering things.
[无法听清] 在回答问题。
>> Yeah. I think
>> 是的。我认为
one of the reasons why I always
~!@#$%^&*()
go back to ICN,
返回首尔仁川国际机场。
even though I departed many times is because
即使我多次离开是因为
as an approach to bring together
作为一种汇集不同观点的方法
various concepts that go
各种不同的概念包括
from data to computation,
从数据到计算，
it is extremely intriguing and there's
它极其有趣，而且还有
an aspect when you come
一种特质在你到来时候展现出来
to the variability of
变化多端的
data sources that has inherently to
数据源本质上必须具备的~!@#$%^&*()
do with the centralization
处理中心化
and it goes back to comments
并且回到了评论内容上
made about the
做出了关于
decentralization of computation.
计算的去中心化。
Maybe performance is one of
也许性能是其中之一
the aspects and I
也许性能是其中之一，方面和我同意如果你会得到
agree if you'd get
同意如果你会得到
30 percent more performance,
提高了30%的性能，
nobody's going to be particularly excited.
没有人会特别兴奋。
But the aspect of
但是我发现的非常~!@#$%^&*()
decentralization that I find very
我发现的非常分散化
interesting is when decentralization becomes
有趣的是当去中心化变得
more of a qualitative,
更多的是一种定性的，
maybe governance-driven aspect than
或许更多的是一种由治理驱动的方面，
a pure performance aspect,
一个纯粹的性能方面，
bringing diverse systems together,
将各种不同的系统整合在一起，
each with a data governance aspect.
将各种不同的系统整合在一起，每个系统都具有数据治理方面的特征，其元数据随之附加。
Their metadata being attached to it.
它们的元数据随之附加。
You will need to
您将需要
convert from one system to the other.
从一个系统转换到另一个系统。
You need adaptation and processing functions.
你需要适应和处理功能。
You add an aspect of decentralization to
你增加了一个去中心化的方面至
your system that's indeed
你的系统确实是
significantly different
显著不同
than the systems we know today.
比我们今天所知道的系统。
That is a very good comment
这是一个非常好的评论。
that NDNs are very good in pushing data out,
NDNs在推送数据方面非常出色，
but they're not very good and
但它们在这方面并不是很好，
really in a decentralized manner,
但它们在这方面并不是很好，真正以分散的方式来管理和处理数据。
managed and process data.
管理和处理数据。
That's the part that intrigues me about
这就是让我感兴趣的部分关于
a data-centric architecture like
像这样的以数据为中心的架构
ICN as an [inaudible] NDN specifically.
ICN作为一个[听不清的]，特别是NDN。
But you have the ability to
但是你有能力去
inherently accommodate
天生适应
decentralization aspect.
分散化方面。
You have the ability to integrate
你有能力整合
the computational part into
将计算部分整合进
it which makes it
将计算部分整合进它，这确实非常有趣。
indeed very interesting.
确实非常有趣。
That was my question.
这就是我的问题。
I put it on Slack, but I realize you
我把它放在Slack上了，但我意识到你可能看不到Slack上的问题。
probably can't read the Slack question.
你可能看不到Slack上的问题。
[LAUGHTER]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> I'm repeating it.
我在重复它。
That's the part that when
那是当时的那部分。
we looked at the decentralization of
我们考察了去中心化的情况
computed wasn't really one that is
计算并不是一个真正的……
necessarily driven by the performance aspect,
必然是由性能方面推动的，
but it's driven by aspects of
性能方面的驱动，
localization that may require me
可能需要我的本地化
to actually pick a compute source
实际上选择一个计算资源
that is nearer to me.
离我更近的是。
I cut very similar requirements in his slides
他的幻灯片中我剪辑了非常相似的要求。
about computed may want
关于计算的可能需要
to be very local to you.
可能需要对你有很强的局部性。
It gives qualitative aspects of
它提供了定性的方面
a system that is potentially the driver
一个可能是驱动力的系统
for change rather than
为了改变而不是
the 20 or 30 percent more performance
提高了20%或30%的性能
in comparison to a centralized approach
与集中式方法相比
and that's something we
与集中式方法相比，那是我们越来越想要了解的东西。
increasingly want to understand
我们越来越想要了解
in some of the use cases
在一些使用案例中
we're looking at with three
我们正在查看的是三个
out the identity space,
关于身份空间，
for instance, and the attributes
例如，以及随之而来的属性
that come with it and then you
随之而来的属性，然后你会意识到在
will realize in
将会意识到在
a distributed identity spaces in
分布式身份空间中
how the data with
如何处理具有~!@#$%^&*()
different sources, with different attributes.
不同的来源，具有不同的属性。
Everybody has their own
每个人都有自己的
semantic and it requires
语义上的并且它需要
a networking approach that can deal with
一种能够处理
that heavy degree of decentralization,
那种高度的去中心化，
which I don't think
我认为不会
in particular
特别是
the current Internet that sees is
当前看到的互联网是
a very significant centralization
一个非常显著的集中化
at the moment into
在当前时刻进入
your localized CDN but
进入你的本地化CDN，但
is really designed for.
它真正设计的目的。
That's the aspect that I find intriguing.
这是我觉得有趣的方面。
Again, I don't know if that's an answer
这又是我不知道是否有答案的地方。
and we're working on some of the answers.
我们正在努力寻找一些答案。
But the joint orchestration
但是联合协调工作
that was also mentioned
这也被提到了
between computation or computation data
在计算或计算数据之间
is clearly an aspect.
显然是一个方面。
But it's usually important because again,
但这通常很重要，因为再一次，
the selection of the computation
选择计算方式
will heavily depend on where
将严重依赖于来源地
data is coming from
数据来自于
and where is it tested for,
以及它在哪里被测试，
and it's a very difficult task,
以及它是一个非常艰巨的任务，
it is a very dynamic task.
它是一个非常充满活力的任务。
The dynamicity was mentioned as well,
它的动态性也被提及了，
which is a key aspect as well.
这也是一个关键的方面。
>> Thank you. Ike,
>> 谢谢你。Ike，
since you're the new person,
既然你是新来的，
we said that one way
我们说过一个方式
of creating the community,
来创建社区，
this was a community meeting,
这是一次社区会议，
was actually to bring people
实际上是为了让人们参与进来
from outside the community
来自社区外部
inside the community and you were
社区内部，你是
asking how can NDN help.
询问NDN如何能够提供帮助。
Let's turn the question around
让我们把问题反过来说
and they're just said
他们刚才说
it's not how what NDN
~!@#$%^&*()
may want because that
可能想要，因为那
was one of my questions.
这是我的一个问题。
It was not what NDN also can offer
这不是NDN也能提供的。
but what would be
但是什么会是
needed in NDN for you
需要在NDN中为你~!@#$%^&*()
to maybe mean more interested by it.
可能意味着对它更感兴趣。
I know that for example,
我知道，例如，
in some of the work that I do,
在我所做的一些工作中，
it's actually this idea of having
实际上是这个想法，拥有
more orchestration and
更多的协调和
decentralization more than performance,
去中心化胜过性能，
especially in very highly distributed areas.
特别是在分布非常广泛的地区。
Ike, what are
~!@#$%^&*()
the pain points and
痛点和
what you're doing that may be
你正在做的那可能是
a native data-centric approach
一种本地数据中心的方法
could solve instead of
可以解决的替代方法
something that you add to.
可以添加的东西。
I understand that the client-server issue
我明白客户端-服务器问题
doesn't work but what else?
不起作用，但还有其他办法吗？
>> Yes. Maybe first to describe it better,
是的。或许首先应该更好地描述它，
how I am actually situated in
我实际上是处于
this whole space of industrial networking.
这整个工业网络空间。
I come there from
我来自那里。
the computer science perspective and
从计算机科学的角度来看，
in our research project,
在我们的研究项目中，
we are working together with a lot of
我们正在与很多
chemical engineers and there we
我们正在与很多化学工程师在那里~!@#$%^&*()
typically already see that even what we
我们通常已经看到，即使是我们
now say is not sufficient anymore.
现在说已经不够了。
IP and all the Internet technology,
IP和所有的互联网技术，
even bringing that into
甚至将其带入
the mechanical engineering domain
机械工程领域
is the challenge in itself already.
挑战本身已经是如此。
I think baby steps right now on
我认为现在应该采取细小的步伐。
the way to there and I
我认为现在应该采取细小的步伐，前往那里的路途，我认为那里最大的问题是~!@#$%^&*()
think the biggest issues there are
我认为那里最大的问题是
that the chemical engineers,
我认为那里最大的问题是化学工程师们，至少那些我知道他们习惯于
at least those that I know they are used to
至少那些我知道他们习惯于
having fixed-function devices so
拥有固定功能的设备，所以
they just buy a box, place it somewhere,
他们只是买了一个盒子，把它放在某个地方，
and then everything is fixed
然后一切都解决了
and then works and they don't have to
然后一切都运作起来，他们不必
change anything and if we want to have
改变任何事情，如果我们想要拥有
really these more dynamic solutions,
真的，这些更具动态性的解决方案，
they first have to convince
他们首先必须说服
that something like that is
他们首先必须说服，那样的事情实际上是可以在...管理的。
actually manageable in terms
实际上是可以在...管理的。
of the effort that needs to be put in
所需投入的努力
there so that they don't have
以便它们不会
to put extensive amounts
投入大量的
of time in that to make it work,
投入大量的时间去使它工作，
but that they basically can just put a box
但他们基本上可以只是放置一个盒子
there and let it run.
他们基本上可以只是放置一个盒子在那里并让它运行。
Then obviously also what
那显然也是什么
Dirk was saying regarding the orchestration
德克谈到了关于管弦乐编排的事情。
and how to put the compute and
以及如何将计算和~!@#$%^&*()
the data paths together.
将数据路径连接起来。
That's also something, I
这也是一件事情，我
think that might be a pain point
认为那可能是一个痛点
because right now they
因为现在他们
have really good control
有非常好的控制力
or how they place down
或者他们是如何放置下来的
functionality and just by placing the boxes
功能性，仅仅通过放置这些盒子
accordingly in their setup
可以适当地安排它们的设置位置
and if we want to have that
如果我们想要那样做，
in a more thermodynamic way,
用一种更热力学的方式，
I think it's really crucial for
我认为这真的非常关键，
them to have this in a way
that it's simple to define.
that it's simple to define
它很容易定义。
how those different aspects
这些不同方面如何
interact like I showed on my slide if we,
互动就像我在幻灯片上展示的那样，如果我们，
for example, depending on what kind
例如，这取决于是哪种类型
of data is now coming out,
正在出现的数据类型是什么，取决于它是什么形式。
on what form it is
它是什么形式
coming out where we want to send it.
它出现在我们想要发送它的地方。
That this can really be defined in
这确实可以被定义在
an easy-to-understand way for
一种易于理解的方式来
them without that much overhead.
它们不需要那么多的开销。
That's at least what
至少那是什么
I would say about this topic.
我会这样说关于这个话题。
I think right now,
我认为现在，
in the middle between
在中间
the people that could deploy the stuff in
部署这些东西的人在
the shop loss and the NDN community trying to
商店的损失以及NDN社区正在尝试如何部署这些东西的人在…找出它如何可以被部署
find out how it can be deployed
找出它如何可以被部署
there having the outside view on both,
他们对两者都有外部的看法，
or I'll save you on both domains I think.
或者我想，我会在这两个领域都救助你。
>> The good name you ambassador.
>> 你的好名声，大使。
>> That would be a way as.
~!@#$%^&*()
[LAUGHTER].
[笑声].
>> I'm not seeing a lot
我没有看到很多
of questions on Slack.
在Slack上，人们仍在讨论许多问题。
of the previous final break.
上一次最后的休息。
>> Maria, could I share a comment, quickly?
>> 玛利亚，我能快速分享一个评论吗？
>> Yes, go ahead. I was going to say is
>> 好的，请说。我本来想说的是
anybody also from
有谁还来自~!@#$%^&*()
the audience? Go ahead Rute.
观众？请继续，Rute。
>> Just quickly. I agree with Ike,
>> 我同意Ike的观点，很快地说一下。
but I want just to comment something.
但我只想评论一些事情。
What I've been transmitting
我一直在传达的内容
does not relate with a performance.
与表现无关。
This is not about who is best.
这与谁最好无关。
The fact is that It's not just
事实上，这不仅仅是
convincing the mechanical engineer,
说服机械工程师，
Over the last,
在过去的，
I don't five, six years,
我不是五、六年。
I've had talks with large vendors trying to
我已经与大型供应商进行了谈话，试图
convince them to do some research
说服他们进行一些研究
on NDN to understand,
to convince them to conduct some research on NDN to understand, as Dirk saying, the capability, for instance,
as Dirk saying, the capability, for instance,
正如德克所说的，例如，能力，
to provide
提供
decentralized data synchronization,
分布式数据同步，
which is
分布式数据同步是一个他们实际上遇到的关键问题。
a crucial problem they have actually.
他们实际上遇到的一个关键问题。
To understand better if It could
理解它是否可能
support an instinct timing model, etc.
支持本能时序模型等。
We have the same problem. The answer is no.
我们有同样的问题。答案是不。
They don't want to do It
他们不想做这个。
because they don't see any value with.
因为他们认为这没有任何价值。
If I say okay,
如果我说好的，
but then the end does have already
但是最后的结局确实已经到来了
some distributed synchronization approaches
一些分布式同步方法
which are very,
它们是非常，
very interesting because as Dirk said,
它们非常有趣，因为正如Dirk所说，
It allows us to have
它让我们能够拥有
the computer and the network
计算机和网络
also the writer part.
还有作者部分。
The answer is always we can do
答案总是我们可以做到
It with other approaches.
它与其他方法相比。
In my slides, I don't know if you
在我的幻灯片中，我不知道你~!@#$%^&*()
saw that we are comparing NDN.
看到我们正在比较NDN。
Again, It's not the performance it's
再一次，这不是性能问题，而是
trying to understand also
Once again, this is not a performance issue, but rather the discovery aspects and trying to understand also.
the discovery aspects and
发现方面以及
the synchronization of the prefix.
前缀的同步。
It's okay to understand if we can say,
如果我们能说的话，理解起来是没问题的。
"Hey, here's a concrete advantage."
“嘿，这是一个具体的优势。”
We are comparing it with COTI which is
我们正在将其与COTI进行比较，后者是
an open-source decentralized approach
一个开源的去中心化方法
deadlocked by a large vendor.
被一个大供应商僵持住了。
Quite interesting for
非常有趣的是
a collaborative communications in IoT.
物联网中的协作通信。
It's a regular application
这是一个常规应用程序。
by it's oriented communication
它是面向通信的。
approach that does discovery and
它采用的方法进行发现和
data synchronization.
数据同步。
Basically, they find it is enough.
基本上，他们认为这已经足够了。
It's not so much whether NDN
从计算的角度来看或
from a theoretical perspective
从理论的角度来看
does have interesting properties.
确实具有有趣的特性。
We actually have to prove that or at least to
我们实际上必须证明那个，或者至少要
show it running a
证明它在运行一个
little bit like Ike is saying.
有点像Ike所说的。
We need to know why they install NDN,
我们需要知道他们为什么要安装NDN，
so that we can show, hey,
以便我们可以展示，嘿，
here's how this runs as
这是它如何运行的。
such and we did a little bit more than that.
我们还做了一些额外的工作。
>> Is it okay if I add to that?
>> 我可以补充一点吗？
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> 好的，请说。
>> I completely agree with Rute and in fact,
>> 我完全同意Rute的看法，实际上，
that is our observations as well.
这也是我们的观察结果。
If there is something that
如果有什么事情
already works with IP or
已经可以通过IP工作了或者
can be made to work
可以被使得工作
by adding a little bit of code,
通过添加一点代码，
or even if it's not elegant,
或即使它不优雅，
even if it's cumbersome and hodgepodge,
即使它笨重且混杂不堪，
they'll say I'd rather do that,
他们会说，我宁愿做那个，
than go over to NDN.
宁愿去NDN。
That is partly where I
那部分是我在哪里
came up with a performance as well one.
他们也提出了一个表演的想法。
They want to see something
他们想看到一些东西
else big, whatever that is.
他们想看到一些东西，如果他们面临的问题是其他的大问题，不管那是什么。
If they are facing a problem that they
他们如果面临一个他们无法解决的问题，
are absolutely not able to solve,
他们绝对无法解决，
and then we give them the solution,
然后我们给他们提供解决方案，
yes, there'll be more willing to take it.
是的，会有更多人愿意接受它。
But let's be honest, you can always
但让我们诚实一点，你总是可以
somehow do whether it's
不管它是否是
hodgepodge or not elegant.
不管它是否是杂乱无章或不雅观。
You can figure out a way to do
你可以想办法去做
something similar than IP,
~!@#$%^&*()
maybe it won't scale as much
也许它不会那么容易扩展
or maybe it's not as horizontal,
也许它不是那么横向发展的，
but you can somehow figure out a way to do it
但你可以设法找到一个方法去做到这一点
and they're more willing
而且他们更愿意
to go along those lines.
沿着那些思路去做。
That was fair.
那是公平的。
The other point was,
其他的观点是，
if the Endian community can make it easy,
如果Endian社区能够使其变得简单，
age of course show the
年龄当然会显示出来。
benefits can make it easy,
福利可以使事情变得简单，
have codes tabs or plugins that say,
有代码、标签或插件说，
"Hey, just put that in here
嘿，就把那个放在这里
and you can keep your code as is,
你可以保持你的代码原样，
but you can do all of these added features."
但是你可以加入所有这些额外的功能。
If you can be added
但是你可以加入~!@#$%^&*()
features to something that's already there,
为现有的事物添加特性，
I believe that the industry
我相信该行业
would be more receptive.
将会更加欢迎。
>> I was going to say this is actually
>> 我本来要说这实际上是
a perfect segue into the next panel,
一个完美的过渡到下一个讨论小组，
which is going to look a little bit
将会稍微看起来有一点
about these aspects and I
will look a little bit about these aspects and I think what you are
think what you are
认为你是什么
saying everyone is, I think,
认为每个人都是，我认为，
a good take home message for
一个值得深思的家庭寓言教训
the community in the sense
社区在这个意义上
that there's a lot of capabilities,
在这方面有很多能力，
and worse than that,
而且更糟的是，
I think there's a lot of needs.
我认为有很多需求。
NDN has a lot of solution and I
NDN有很多解决方案，而我
think maybe the community should do
我认为也许社区应该做得更好工作，
a better job,
做得更好的工作，
for lack of a better word,
为了更恰当地表达(如果没有更合适的词汇的话)，
at showing that these capabilities exist.
在展示这些能力存在方面。
For you guys who are
对于你们这些人来说
in industry another issue
在工业领域，另一个问题
that is always raised is the issue of cost.
总是被提出的另一个问题是成本问题。
You're mentioning that just
您提到的仅仅是
adding a few lines of code,
增加了几行代码，
it's not very good,
它不是很好，
but it doesn't take time.
但它不耗费时间。
It doesn't take a lot of resources
它不需要很多资源。
and doesn't cost much money.
而且花费不多。
That's one thing. I think
这是一方面，我认为
there's also this issue of money.
这还涉及到金钱的问题。
We have time for one or two questions
我们有时间回答一到两个问题。
from the audience.
来自观众的。
But the people in the audience who are
但是来自观众的那些人，
the big players in the NDN community,
大型网络延迟容忍网络(NDN)社区的主要参与者，
what would you answer to the question of
~!@#$%^&*()
this panel who is
这个面板是谁？
actually asking for better solutions?
实际上是在寻求更好的解决方案吗？
Is anybody want to talk?
有人想聊天吗？
If not, I'm going to ask someone so.
如果没有人想聊天，我就去找别人聊。
Wow, you guys are shy today.
哇，你们今天都很害羞啊。
>> I'm going to ask a question.
>> 我要提一个问题。
>> Go ahead.
>> 请说。
>> This is interesting discussion
>> 这是有趣的讨论
about performance.
关于表现。
So far, I mean,
到目前为止，我的意思是，
the performance of NDN has not
到目前为止，NDN的表现还没有
been great because it's an experimental.
达到了预期的效果，因为它还处于实验阶段。
It's understandable.
这是可以理解的。
But do you see
但是你看见了吗？
the lack of performance
性能的缺失
driving people away from NDN?
将人们从NDN赶走？
>> Srikathyayani do yo wanted to answer?
>> ~!@#$%^&*()
>> Sure. As I said, the key is, I mean,
>> 当然。正如我所说，关键是，我的意思是，
if we step back a little bit
如果我们稍微退后一点儿
from just the performance,
从仅仅是表现来看，
industry is set in their ways,
业界固守旧习，
for lack of a better word.
因缺乏更合适的词汇。
Because there's so much code,
因为代码量很大，
there's so much history,
有着如此悠久的历史，
there's so much time was spent in
有着如此悠久的历史，在其中花费了很多时间来
developing everything that they have;
发展他们所拥有的一切；
the systems, the code-based
系统、基于代码的
software, all of that.
软件，所有这些。
For that to change,
为了改变这一点，
you need a driver.
你需要一个司机。
Now, one of them
现在，他们中的一个
can definitely be performance.
肯定可以是表现。
I think what we're saying is we need
我认为我们在说的是我们需要
whatever that driver is
无论那个司机是什么
at that bigger push needs to come.
那更大的推动力需要到来。
A, it can be if it's performance,
那么，如果是性能的话，它可以成为……
yes, surely that'll be a driver.
是的，当然那将是一个驱动因素。
The other thing that will also
另一个同样会
facilitate is if it
便利是如果它
is easy because let's say,
容易是因为假设，
I have my Kubernetes app,
我有我的 Kubernetes 应用程序，
then hey, we all know
那么嘿，我们都知道
there are plenty of problems with Kubernetes.
Kubernetes存在许多问题。
It doesn't do discovery, it
它不进行服务发现，它
doesn't adapt to networks
它不适应网络变化
[OVERLAPPING]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> If you can say, "Hey,
>> 如果你能说，“嘿，
just put this NDN plugin on and just put
只需安装这个NDN插件然后就放上去
these on all these nodes are clusters and
将这些安装在所有这些节点上的集群中，
devices and suddenly
设备，突然
you'll have these capabilities.
你将拥有这些能力。
You'll still get everything
你仍然会得到一切。
else that you have.
你拥有的其他一切。
That if we can make it easy to transition,
如果我们能让转变变得容易，
those added benefits are
那些额外的好处是
likely to be accepted.
很可能会被接受。
I don't know if that answers your question.
我不知道那是否回答了你的问题。
>> It does. What we
确实如此。我们
NDN makes a lot of calls easier.
NDN让很多通话变得更加容易。
But when you give users
但是当你给用户
things that make their life easier,
让他们的生活变得更轻松的事情，
the next question they ask is,
他们接下来提出的问题是，
how I can make this perform better?
我怎样才能使它表现得更好？
Kubernetes, this is great with NDN,
Kubernetes，这与NDN很搭。
then they're going to complain that,
那么他们就会抱怨说，
well, where is my performance?
那么，我的表现在哪里？
How do you address that question?
你是如何回答那个问题的？
>> That's a very good point. That is where I
那是一个非常好的观点。那是我~!@#$%^&*()
think the merging IP and
think the merging IP and NDN needs to happen 认为IP和NDN的合并需要发生
NDN needs to happen
NDN需要发生。
a little better because let's be honest,
有点好转，因为让我们诚实一点，
IP is not going anywhere.
IP不会消失。
So the question is, how can we
所以问题是，我们怎样能够~!@#$%^&*()
add the benefits of NDN?
增加NDN的好处？
To your question is, how
Regarding your question, it is about how...
can you make the performance better?
你能提高性能吗？
A lot of research is happening already on IP.
已经有很多关于知识产权的研究在进行中。
The question is, can those translate?
这个问题是，那些能翻译吗？
Not everything has to be done in NDN.
并不是所有的事情都必须用NDN来完成。
You can just say NDN brings
您只需说NDN带来了
all these additional features
所有这些附加功能
in a much more easier manner.
以一种更加简单的方式。
But yes, you can still
但是，你仍然可以
maybe do your optimizations on IP.
也许可以在IP上进行你的优化。
Also coming to the performance,
也谈到了性能表现，
the few points that I mentioned,
我提到的那几点，
NDN does perform better.
NDN的性能确实更好。
In fact, in the case of what
实际上，在什么情况下
we found is extreme dynamism of resources.
我们发现的是资源的极端动态性。
Kubernetes currently doesn't handle that.
Kubernetes 目前还不能处理这个问题。
There are a few pockets
有一些小口袋
where NDN performs better.
NDN表现得更好。
The key is how do you then integrate
关键是你如何去整合
that with everything else?
你如何将其与其他所有事物整合在一起？
Overall, the performance
总体而言，表现
increases without losing what
增长而不失去已有的东西
they already have.
他们已经拥有的。
I don't know if that helps.
我不知道这是否有帮助。
>> Yes. I think we are all out of time.
是的。我认为我们的时间都用完了。
I took some little notes.
我做了一些简短的笔记。
If I a look at the notes here and again,
如果我再次查看这里的笔记，
just note this is a very good segue
请注意，这是一个非常好的过渡。
into your own panel.
进入你自己的面板。
I think there's a question of making
我认为这里有一个问题需要解决。
sure that NDN essentially
确信NDN本质上
is known as a potential solution in
被认为是一个潜在的解决方案在
the worlds that others are dealing with.
他人正在应对的世界。
That the performance is
这样的表现是
known who are not aware of these things.
这些事情有些人是知道的，有些人却不知道。
On the need to have a better integration of
需要更好地整合
the data systems with
需要更好地整合数据系统与主要功能进行~!@#$%^&*()
the major functionality going
需要与主要功能进行
back with to Dirk's question,
回到Dirk的问题，
if data is the solution, what is the problem?
如果数据是解决方案，那么问题是什么？
I think it's having
我认为它正在
all these systems that are distributed,
所有这些分布式的系统，
talk together in a
协同工作的方式，
functional and productive,
功能性和生产力强的，
and performing way.
功能性和生产力强的，并且表现出色的方式。
Thank you very much to the four of you.
非常感谢你们四位。
to the audience.
非常感谢各位观众。
You were too quiet, but that's okay.
你太安静了，不过没关系。
I think here in
我认为这里在东海岸，是午餐时间。
the East Coast, it's lunchtime.
东海岸，现在是午餐时间。
I think Dirk, you are leaving for dinner
我觉得Dirk，你要去吃晚饭了。
and I would love
我很想
this team to continue the discussion.
继续讨论这个团队。
Thank you very much everyone
非常感谢大家。
and we'll probably see
我们很可能会见到
one another in some other Zoom
我们很可能会见到，在某个不同的Zoom会议中，彼此相遇。
at one point. Thank you.
在某个时刻。谢谢你。
>> Thank you. Bye-bye.
>> 谢谢你。再见。
[OVERLAPPING]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Thank you, everyone.
>> 谢谢大家。
We will be back at 1:00 p.m.
我们将在下午1点回来。